<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>People on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/people/</link><description>Recent content in People on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:37:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Couple of things that went unnoticed</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/couple-of-things-that-went-unnoticed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:01:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/couple-of-things-that-went-unnoticed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last July marks the Quadrennial year working in an MNC. These years had taught me several valuable lessons. Learnt either from first-hand experience or learning from others action. What I learnt is that our fundamentals are flawed as several important things are not taught at young age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 2 important things that must be included in curriculum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.in/search?q=define%20career&amp;amp;cad=h">Career&lt;/a> vs. &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.in/search?q=define+job&amp;amp;cad=h">Job&lt;/a> : In earlier generation, its pride to be working with an employer for long duration (say, in terms years or decades). I have part of several farewells where in people will be treated well for part of the establishment and retiring is like a big event. That was the day in past. I don’t come across those celebration in recent times. One of my team mate, recently joined states that this is his 5th employer in 8 years. In this 8-year-long career he has been working with several domain and several tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shouldn’t there be some regulation – road side shops</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/shouldnt-there-be-some-regulation-road-side-shops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/shouldnt-there-be-some-regulation-road-side-shops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Waking up at the morning, after finishing morning-activities I noticed there was no water. I should have checked the water can in the night. Duh!! Should have called the water can vendor if I reached home came earlier. He did delivered the cans after a call and waiting for a hour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Breakfast time. Rushed out to road-side eatery. While waiting for dishes to be prepared, had conversation with the owner-cum-server, came to know that the continuous rain for 3 days the last week has affected their business. And, things went worse as they couldn’t repay the debt on that week. Still waiting for the dishes to get prepared, hunger made it the longest 10 minutes. Finally, it got ready. Then came another obstacle – traffic cop. He was questioning the owner, on whose permission they are running the stall on the road-side.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Striving with Contextual speakers</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/striving-with-contextual-speakers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/striving-with-contextual-speakers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you connected to WiFi?, isn’t it slow?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First part of above sentence is objectively denotes ‘WiFi’. The second part contextually denotes ‘WiFi’ through the word – ‘it’.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/context">Merriam-Webster&lt;/a>, Context is defined as,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The parts of a discourse that surround a word or passage and can throw light on its meaning&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Every tech giant is boasting that their digital assistants can understand our contextual conversation. Indeed it is a big step for machines to understand our natural speech.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>