<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on Dheepak&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on Dheepak&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Factfulness</title>
      <link>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-11-25-factfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-11-25-factfulness/</guid>
      <description>While browsing the web around data visualization, someone recommended Hans Rosling&amp;rsquo;s TED talk. You must watch the video if you like visualization or you like listening to story. While learning about him, I came across this book Factfulness.
     Book Name Author Subject Area Pages     Factfulness: Ten reasons we&amp;rsquo;re wrong about the world Hans Rosling Data-based thinking 342      About author Hans Rosling was a Swedish physician, academic, and public speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams</title>
      <link>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-10-20-why-we-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-10-20-why-we-sleep/</guid>
      <description>During an interview in my early days of career HR asked me how I manage day-to-day pressure that I face. I answered that I&amp;rsquo;ll doze off and manage to move on from previous day&amp;rsquo;s not-so-pleasant events. I told this anecdote whenever someone makes fun of my sleepiness. Lo and behold this book shone light on events happening inside the cranium while we sleep, and states that we do able to handle emotions and bad memories through good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Thing: Uncommon Sense for The Thoughtful Investor</title>
      <link>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-05-30-important-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-05-30-important-things/</guid>
      <description>Book Name Author Subject Area Pages     The Most Important Thing: Uncommon Sense for The Thoughtful Investor Howard S. Marks Investment 196    About author Howard Marks is an American investor, associated with Oaktree Capital Management, the largest investor in distressed securities worldwide. His memos are popular among investors community
Second-level thinking   Successful investing requires thoughtful attention to many separate aspects, all at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits - Notes</title>
      <link>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-02-11-atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2021-02-11-atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>Book Name Author Subject Area Pages     Atomic Habits James Clear Habit building 271            Cover page - Atomic Habits    Notes from each of the chapter
Introduction How I learnt about Habits
  A habit is a routine or behaviour that is performed regularly - and in many cases, automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money - Notes</title>
      <link>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2020-11-28-psych-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/notes/2020-11-28-psych-money/</guid>
      <description>This is about The Psychology of Money by Morgan Housel, a Columnist. This book became a sensation in the #fintwit. Many tweeters recommended the book and I preordered it on Amazon.
        Cover page    The book is crisp - 240 pages grouped into 20 chapters, each having few stories to explain actions behind money decisions.
Notes from each of the chapter</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
