<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Review on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/review/</link><description>Recent content in Review on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:10:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 Years of Data, Deadlines and Growth</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/04/3-years-of-data-deadlines-and-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/04/3-years-of-data-deadlines-and-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the blogs for some years now. I came across the annual reviews on the FreeFinCal site; it&amp;rsquo;s a shame I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall the exact year. My guess would be somewhere between 2018 and 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the pandemic, I started subscribing to the Substacks. I noticed almost everyone who is regularly writing is reviewing the annual performance. And I always wanted to write one for myself. The birthdays, New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eves, and financial year-end—all of them provided a chance to write. All these days were an opportunity to sit down and look back at what has happened.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How was 2023?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very common to look back what happened after an event. This post is about looking back at the past year through various criteria,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Personal life&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Career&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hobby&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="personal-life">Personal Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Work-life balance oculd have been better, its not like the employer is squeezing me. But its my ability to give priority to the family. If at all one thing I need to work on this year, that would be more time spent with family and cultivating memories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 1</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 14:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>The 2010&amp;rsquo;s was my 20&amp;rsquo;s. I was in the middle of under graduate course when the decade begun. An average engineering graduate who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what engineering really was or what&amp;rsquo;s the future is offering. The end of year marks the recruitment to my current employer. Yes right, I&amp;rsquo;m with the employer for almost a decade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IIRC 13k was my 1&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup> my first salary. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall how I spent it, guess gave it to my mom. My first smartphone was Galaxy Ace with 142 MB of memory (now there are plenty of apps that comes with larger memory footprint than the phone).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>