<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 Years of Data, Deadlines and Growth</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/04/3-years-of-data-deadlines-and-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/04/3-years-of-data-deadlines-and-growth/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the blogs for some years now. I came across the annual reviews on the FreeFinCal site; it&amp;rsquo;s a shame I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall the exact year. My guess would be somewhere between 2018 and 2020.
During the pandemic, I started subscribing to the Substacks. I noticed almost everyone who is regularly writing is reviewing the annual performance. And I always wanted to write one for myself. The birthdays, New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eves, and financial year-end—all of them provided a chance to write.</description></item><item><title>IPL: Ways to see beyond Scoreboard</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/03/ipl-ways-to-see-beyond-scoreboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/03/ipl-ways-to-see-beyond-scoreboard/</guid><description>Data visualization is one field that has kept me captivated for some time now. The graphics published in sites like FT, Reuters, or NYT made me wonder why I don&amp;rsquo;t spend time on the skill.
The good volume and variety of data that is available is available all the time. Share market—daily; IPL—yearly. I find each of the cricket matches, no matter if they are Test, ODI, or T20, generates so much data.</description></item><item><title>Over-confidence is the safety risk</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/12/over-confidence-is-the-safety-risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/12/over-confidence-is-the-safety-risk/</guid><description>Few years ago, I was working in a Chennai, 500 KM away from Coimbatore, where my family resides. The usual trip between the cities is on long weekends, so does the large crowd settled in Singara Chennai. With a huge crowd looking to travel back on long weekends, reserving a seat was not easiest thing to do. I booked my ticket a week back and in relaxed manner went to boarding point.</description></item><item><title>How I'm planning to get started on Deep Learning?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/11/how-im-planning-to-get-started-on-deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/11/how-im-planning-to-get-started-on-deep-learning/</guid><description>This post is to describe how I find the book Meta Learning: How To Learn Deep Learning And Thrive In The Digital World is giving me a hope and road map to learn Deep Learning. Not only learning DL and also where to go from there viz Kaggle.
Who am I? I&amp;rsquo;m part of Data landscape for more than a decade now. I started as ETL developer, then evolved into Data Engineer.</description></item><item><title>Event Update: M2W Conclave 2.0</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</guid><description>Intro This is about an event or a gathering around the theme of personal finance. The crowd gathered is through the Youtube channel - Muthaleetukalam (முதலீட்டுக்களம்) translates to &amp;lsquo;Investment sector&amp;rsquo;, thanks Google. This is coordinated by iThought Wealth&amp;rsquo;s Shyam Shekhar through his milestones2wealth, a portal to make Making Small Investors THINK BIG!.
div.rightBox { position: absolute; right: 0; width: 230px; height: 250px; border: 3px solid grey; } My PoV I started following the channel during the lockdown, just like million other self-proclaimed investors.</description></item><item><title>Event Update: Consecration</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/event-update-consecration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/event-update-consecration/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the midway between an atheist, agnostic and a religious person. My particiaption in events based out of religious tradition, is almost always doubtful. Yet, I was part of this community gathering, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover the event.
When a temple gets built, it deserves sequence of rituals that adds spiritual and religious power to the deity living in the temple. As it is a belief based system, logical questioing doesn&amp;rsquo;t end well.</description></item><item><title>My Prayer</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</guid><description>To start with I&amp;rsquo;m not a religious person. Meaning I don&amp;rsquo;t strictly follow the religious activities, I do constantly question the practises. I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether I&amp;rsquo;m an atheist or an agnostic. But I do believe there could be some powerful entity. Could be a god, family of gods or nature.
When I was living abroad for the work purpose, I need a social interaction. That made me to visit temple every week, almost.</description></item><item><title>Analog Clock</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/07/analog-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/07/analog-clock/</guid><description>First we started with a circle. The dial is composed of a bigger circle and a smaller one - a center point.
With the dial is in place, next step is to add arms of the clock. The end result should have 3 arms - depicting hours, minutes and seconds. To have quicker feedback we started with seconds arm.
Drawing the radius solves the initial position of seconds arm.</description></item><item><title>Investing in real estates</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</guid><description>This is a write up on my thoughts abour real estate as investment. The real estate implies plot as well as the home.
To describe my disinterest towards RE, first we should see how the system works with respect to RE. To make it clear I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about REITs.
This is entirely unregulated space. Meaning, there is no check and balance to help the consumers. With no regulations, the black money is very very common.</description></item><item><title>Learnings from working with external teams</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</guid><description>With the recent change in the role from data engineer to lead data engineer, I&amp;rsquo;m regularly interacting with different teams, both upstream and downstream. It had become routine to have meetings with the counterparties to understand their difficulties. After all, we are a tree but a part of a forest. Diversity factor It might annoy us to hear about diversity from the MNCs again and again. However, for the proper functioning of the organization, it is essential to have associates from various backgrounds.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on recent changes in work place</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</guid><description>The last few weeks have been tough. The problem seems to originate from all three avenues: life, work, and the social circle. My child is demanding that I play with her more regularly and for more time. By size, my social circle is small. I feel the size further shrinks due to my inability to speak or interact with my close friends. Even though the friends usually accept the fact that life is getting busier, the crack appears nonetheless.</description></item><item><title>Tax and Death</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</guid><description>.. in this world nothing can be said to be certain, except death and taxes
&amp;amp;mdash Benjamin Franklin[1]
Tax I came across a meme - Tax is a subscription fee to the state we live in. In a way the statement is true.
You owe some money to the land where you live. Most of the countries collect it income tax, some countries do survive without collecting income tax[2].</description></item><item><title>Reflection on daily journaling</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</guid><description>The last quarter of 2023 was spent away from family for work related in a nordic country. The country is small. The Population density is much smaller. From the land of crowded spaces, this was taking a toll. Staying away from friends and family adds to this as well.
Just to fight off the boredom and depression, I resumed filling the journal on daily basis. Following are the reflections of the process.</description></item><item><title>Index Movement - Visualization</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</guid><description>Why? To keep myself from overthinking or having negative thoughts, I should focus my energy on something creative. Also, the creativity should pique my curiosity. Essentially, I should spend time learning something. Personal finance is something that we monitor and learn about in a daily manner. The PF has a variety of numbers and data to deal with. It&amp;rsquo;s more like clay that allows you to come up with any sculpture.</description></item><item><title>How was 2023?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s very common to look back what happened after an event. This post is about looking back at the past year through various criteria,
Personal life Career Hobby Finance Personal Life Work-life balance oculd have been better, its not like the employer is squeezing me. But its my ability to give priority to the family. If at all one thing I need to work on this year, that would be more time spent with family and cultivating memories.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/visuals/clock/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/visuals/clock/</guid><description>Analog Clock --</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/visuals/cwc2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/visuals/cwc2023/</guid><description>Cricket World Cup 2023 .tooltip { position: absolute; font-family: monospace; pointer-events: none; background: silver; color: black; /* width: 400px; */ text-align: left; border-radius: 6px; padding: 5px 5px; left: 50%; margin-left: -60px; z-index: 1; } .tooltip::after { content: ""; position: relative; top: 100%; /* left: 0; */ margin-left: -5px; border-width: 8px; border-style: solid; border-color: transparent transparent transparent transparent; } /* .cat_Visualization { fill: orange; } */ /* .cat_Opinion { fill: red; stroke: black; } */ .</description></item><item><title>Meetings are bad</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re part of a workforce, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand when I say meetings are bad. How to make it better or avoid it becoming worser? By removing the uncertainity from the equation.
Case 1: A message from your spouse It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekday. You&amp;rsquo;re in a middle of a task which should be completed in next few hours. Your phone beeps. There is a message from your spouse.
We need to talk.</description></item><item><title>Fear + Confusion + Hope = Life?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear-confusion-hope-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear-confusion-hope-life/</guid><description>This is a very, very small post.
I always wonder if uncertainty is bad, possibly the worst feature of life, or may be a bug in life. But uncertainty is not something new that we tend to experience recently. Since the earliest times, uncertainty has been part of life. Thinking out loud, waking up next morning is as uncertain as the weather.
Fear The Earth has gone through several extinctions before taking its current form.</description></item><item><title>Experience with raising PR</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</guid><description>This post deals with my experience on contributing to the open source project - Microsoft Documentation.
My first PR This is not my first PR to an OSS. My very first contribution was to foambubble/foam. The pull request adds licence file to the repo. Yea, I know. This may not qualifies for core technical task. Nevertheless its my contribution. This lead to my Github badge - Pull Shark.
I started interacting with the developers on the fix on April 14th 2021.</description></item><item><title>Why Data Visualization</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/why-data-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/why-data-visualization/</guid><description>Why I chose to pursue a journey in Data Visualization? This post is an explainer to the above question.
What do I do for living? Data Engineering is my day job. SQL and Python have fed me and kept me going for last decade. For the uninitiated, the work involves fetching data from several sources and loading into desired target. The source and target could be a database, API endpoint, or file.</description></item><item><title>What do you pray for</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</guid><description>Consoling a crying child Last week, my kid fell ill. It was a viral fever with cold. Due to the intense cold, she was struggling to breathe and had ear pain. We were constantly clearing up the nasal passage and helping her with breathing. However, she was helpless with ear pain. As per the pediatrician&amp;rsquo;s instructions, we gave her a tonic to relieve her ear pain. The medicine is not a magic potion to heal instantaneously; it was slow process.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/visuals/sitemap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/visuals/sitemap/</guid><description>Visual Sitemap This is a visual arrangement of blog posts over the years.
.notice{--root-color:#444;--root-background:#eff;--title-color:#fff;--title-background:#7bd;--warning-title:#c33;--warning-content:#fee;--info-title:#fb7;--info-content:#fec;--note-title:#6be;--note-content:#e7f2fa;--tip-title:#5a5;--tip-content:#efe}@media (prefers-color-scheme:dark){.notice{--root-color:#ddd;--root-background:#eff;--title-color:#fff;--title-background:#7bd;--warning-title:#800;--warning-content:#400;--info-title:#a50;--info-content:#420;--note-title:#069;--note-content:#023;--tip-title:#363;--tip-content:#121}}body.dark .notice{--root-color:#ddd;--root-background:#eff;--title-color:#fff;--title-background:#7bd;--warning-title:#800;--warning-content:#400;--info-title:#a50;--info-content:#420;--note-title:#069;--note-content:#023;--tip-title:#363;--tip-content:#121}.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:var(--root-color);background:var(--root-background)}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:var(--title-color);background:var(--title-background)}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:var(--warning-title)}.notice.warning{background:var(--warning-content)}.notice.info .notice-title{background:var(--info-title)}.notice.info{background:var(--info-content)}.notice.note .notice-title{background:var(--note-title)}.notice.note{background:var(--note-content)}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:var(--tip-title)}.notice.tip{background:var(--tip-content)}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:.125em;position:relative} Tip
Each lines represent an year, with published date as dots. Number at the end shows number of posts published over an year
.tooltip { position: absolute; font-family: monospace; pointer-events: none; background: silver; color: black; /* width: 400px; */ text-align: left; border-radius: 6px; padding: 5px 5px; left: 50%; margin-left: -60px; z-index: 1; } .</description></item><item><title>The way a child learns</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</guid><description>Of late I&amp;rsquo;m spending good amount of time with my toddler. The things she learns and the way she communicates is intriguing me. To be frank, I believe almost every kid does the same, more or less. But as I am seeing her development from very close I do observe on how she learns.
Imitation: She imitates us. Whatever we do she tries to replicate us. For example, she tries to saute the imaginary food on her toy kitchen set.</description></item><item><title>Fumbling 145 days long kindle reading streak</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</guid><description>If my memory serves right, Snapchat popularised the streak phenomena. Later on, the amount popularity and stickiness it creates among the user, many companies jumped on the band wagon - fitness trackers, calories trackers and many more. What the streak does is it creates a habit among the users and make them to use the particular service on daily basis. Also, it creates a sense of pride with the longer streak on has.</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3 - v3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v3/</guid><description>This is a follow up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post on same name.
What&amp;rsquo;s new? Tooltip - Earlier, we were employing the browser&amp;rsquo;s native tooltip. With this update we have customised tooltip with publish date and categories along with the title of post. Transitions - On hovering the circles turns green and tooltip pops up. .tooltip { position: absolute; font-family: monospace; pointer-events: none; background: silver; color: black; /* width: 400px; */ text-align: left; border-radius: 6px; padding: 5px 5px; left: 50%; margin-left: -60px; z-index: 1; } .</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3 - v2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/05/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/05/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v2/</guid><description>This is a follow up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post on same name.
There are few changes made to the chart.
Today marker: Instead of drawing a full line for the current year, we are allowing the line to grow with passing day. This is a major change. Transition: The trasnition effects are the major change here. Ironically, the amount of code change is minimum - tbh addition of 2 lines is all that&amp;rsquo;s needed.</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/</guid><description>This is an attempt to recreate the earlier created blog post through D3js.
I&amp;rsquo;m more of backend developer, working predominantly in Python + SQL. But, trying out JS is long time wish, which got fufilled through a Udemy course and some good imspiration.
The visuals can be improved vastly and can add few more options. But this post is to show the progress. Also, this is an attempt to conform that D3JS output can be hosted on our static site.</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</guid><description>Once in a while we stumble into something interesting while we are not looking for it. This is a post on how I came across a chart while going through an online course, the experience in replicating the chart, the lessons I learnt.
The instructor of the course - Course: Data Visualization Fundamentals and Best Practices by ObservableHQ. While going through his website I found this interesting chart - Blog Calendar.</description></item><item><title>Multiple roles of a man</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</guid><description>The 30s are tricky period. Till 20s you can survive with a student or young earner tag. In the late 20s, you experience what the freedom is. And, when you start feeling you can do whatever you can and reach wherever you want to in life. Now you&amp;rsquo;re in your 30s and most likely you got punched at your face.
Why 30s are so tough A simple answer is roles that each person plays.</description></item><item><title>API, Configurations &amp; Database operation</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/api-configurations-database-operation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/api-configurations-database-operation/</guid><description>Right now the project focuses on creating dashboard for Mutual funds, and gradually adding other investement vehicles viz stocks, PPF, and EPF.
Fetching NAVs To track the mutual funds, we come across an API by Yuvaraj Loganathan - MFAPI. Thank you, Yuvaraj. The API gets updated on daily basis and free to access (as in free beer). For our project, which is not intended for any financial gain, this api is the right fit.</description></item><item><title>Osmosis IRL</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</guid><description>Osmosis Osmosis is term all of us come across during our schooling days.
In biology, osmosis is the movement of water molecules from a solution with a high concentration of water molecules to a solution with a lower concentration of water molecules, through a cell&amp;rsquo;s partially permeable membrane.
Water purification through reverse osmosis is one of the popular application in our day to day life.
Do we see anything similar to Osmosis in real life?</description></item><item><title>Project Update - 3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-3/</guid><description>This is continuation in the series about our side project. This post is a follow up to the pervious post on various tools used to build the process of building the application
The Environment Core language used in our project is Python. Python is used to fetch details from API calls, cleaning the API return value, and also writing it into DB. Even though the language is very popular and user ranges from amateurs to big corporations, it undergoes development.</description></item><item><title>Project Update - 2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</guid><description>This is a continuation to previous post on our new side project. Instead of building a spaghetti code that just works, we are approaching the entire process through the industry practise.
For example, the working components are modularised for easier maintenance. These individual modules are built on TDD approach, testing with every step of our development. The test results are passed through coverage to understand how much code is covered under our testing process.</description></item><item><title>Personal help/maid affordability - a social indicator?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</guid><description>One of the major difference between developed and developing nation is the way we treat the labours. Usually when a nation grows it concentrates on creating wealth. The wealth, once gets generated it tends to flock together and the rich gets super rich at the cost of vulnerable populous. Once this gap gets too large, the society becomes unstable.
The struggle between the haves and have-nots are the root cause of most of the civil unrest, gradually turning into civil war, if the gap is left unchecked.</description></item><item><title>Are you envious of younger generation?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</guid><description>Scene 1: During school days Teacher : Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you finish your homework?
Student : We experienced powercut all through the evening. And so, the home
T : Don&amp;rsquo;t say unnecessary reason in your age we were reading under the street lamp.
Scene 2: During college days College student : I need a bike to commute to college.
Parent : In your age we were walking n Kilometers to catch the government bus to college, your generation needs private vehicles at this young age?</description></item><item><title>Project Update - 1</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-1/</guid><description>Everyone of us think(or worry) about future, especially in 30s. Likewise, I worry about financial stability of my future. The retirement comes top of the list among the various worries. And so, I started investement. The investment includes various vahicles - Mutual fund, stocks and fixed components. Investing is a beast; tracking the investment is like taming the beast. For tracking the progress there are (literally) endless apps coming into to market.</description></item><item><title>Migrated to blogdown</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/10/migrated-to-blogdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/10/migrated-to-blogdown/</guid><description>I was using Hugo for static site generation with Beautiful Hugo as a theme. The theme is known for its balancing act between simplicity and proseness for a blog. With Hugo its a fast act to creating and publishing the contents.
It was all good until I wanted to embed a HTML page. iFrame is always there but including the charts, especially interactive ones generated as HTML is tough to embed in the post (at least for me).</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/_meta-credits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/_meta-credits/</guid><description>body { margin: 0; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } .topnav { overflow: hidden; background-color: #FFE4C4; color:black; } .topnav a { float: left; color: #000; text-align: center; padding: 14px 16px; text-decoration: none; font-size: 17px; width: 33.33%; } .topnav a:hover { background-color: #ddd; color: black; } .topnav a.active { background-color: #04AA6D; color: white; } About Credits Changelog Credits If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.</description></item><item><title>What if: Google suspends your account?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/08/what-if-google-suspends-your-account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 09:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/08/what-if-google-suspends-your-account/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;re waking up to your alarm. On turning the alarm off you notice there is some error notification, but you casually swipe it away to get started on the day.
While you&amp;rsquo;re commuting to your office you notice the Whatsapp backup ran into some error, now you ignore it as it&amp;rsquo;s not something important. During your tea-break in office you are opening Google Photos to look at your child&amp;rsquo;s memories. Just like earlier notifications Googl Photos too throw some error at you, now you can&amp;rsquo;t able to download the backed-up photos.</description></item><item><title>How much Income Tax Are We Paying?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/how-much-income-tax-are-we-paying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 08:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/how-much-income-tax-are-we-paying/</guid><description>During the last months of every financial year, there is a tradition, a custom to keep ourselves sane - ranting on tax that we suffered through the year, and any returns we can expect from the taxmen.
In one of the ranting sessions, we had an interesting conversation.
How much tax are we paying?.
What is so interesting?
The tax must be either 25% (new regime) or 30% (old regime).</description></item><item><title>Hugo Site Deployment Using Github Actions</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/hugo-site-deployment-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 19:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/hugo-site-deployment-using-github-actions/</guid><description>This is a small write up about setting up GitHub Actions to deploy Hugo site.
Table of content How I was deploying it earlier? What was the problem there? How does the GitHub Actions helps us here? How I was deploying it earlier? I used to have 2 commits for any changes.
Changes to the posts HTML documents generated through hugo command What was the problem there?</description></item><item><title>Cross compatibility is key</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</guid><description>When my kid was on a mattress, she was hesitant to move around. Later on, with the comfort of the soft surface, she was rolling around without caring about her head getting hurt or gravity.
Everything got changed when we let her crawl on the hard surface in the living room. She was getting hurt quite frequently - sometimes stepping on a toy, or hard landing on her head while rolling on the floor, or simply butting on something at her head level.</description></item><item><title>Notes</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/reads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/reads/</guid><description>* { box-sizing: border-box; } body { padding: 1rem; } /* Just for the fallback layout */ main { max-width: 500px; margin: 0 auto; } article { margin: 1rem 0; } /* Now lets do a Grid-based layout */ @supports (display: grid) { main { max-width: 10000px; margin: 0; } article { margin: 0; } .reads { display: grid; grid-template-columns: repeat(3, minmax(300px, 1fr)); grid-gap: 1rem; } } .reads { font-family: Avenir, Roboto, Helvetica, san-serif; font-size: 80%; } .</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/whoami/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/whoami/</guid><description>body { margin: 0; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } .topnav { overflow: hidden; background-color: #FFE4C4; color:black; } .topnav a { float: left; color: #000; text-align: center; padding: 14px 16px; text-decoration: none; font-size: 17px; width: 33.33%; } .topnav a:hover { background-color: #ddd; color: black; } .topnav a.active { background-color: #04AA6D; color: white; } About Credits Changelog About Me Hey there!
I am Dheepak. I am a self-taught developer and I have been programming since 2014.</description></item><item><title>Yet another tech CEO of Indian origin</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/11/yet-another-tech-ceo-of-indian-origin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 20:06:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/11/yet-another-tech-ceo-of-indian-origin/</guid><description>From co-founder to CEO, Jack Dorsey was carrying Twitter&amp;rsquo;s identity for sometime now. He is not without controversies. Twitter and Facebook came to prominence on somewhat same time. Yet, Facebook became a cash-rich poster boy among the social media, Twitter lagging behind Facebook, unclear how to monetize the Twitter as a product. As a CEO, he was blamed for being CEO on Square and not concentrating on Twitter.
+ Fun fact: Argawal joins the growing ranks of powerful US tech executives of Indian descent.</description></item><item><title>Meta</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/_meta-changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/_meta-changelog/</guid><description> body { margin: 0; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; } .topnav { overflow: hidden; background-color: #FFE4C4; color:black; } .topnav a { float: left; color: #000; text-align: center; padding: 14px; text-decoration: none; font-size: 17px; width: 33.33%; } .topnav a:hover { background-color: #ddd; color: black; } .topnav a.active { background-color: #04AA6D; color: white; } About Credits Changelog Changelog</description></item><item><title>A backend dev's journey into JS world - Part I</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 13:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</guid><description>I use SQL and Python to earn my bread. Being an ETL developer turned Data Engineer, my work is to fetch data from different sources, cleaning it, and making it consumption ready before storing it in some storage space - database, S3 et al.
It&amp;rsquo;s amusing to know that someone will be consuming this data and pull insights from it like a magician pulling a rabbit off his hat. The reporting tools were the go-to place to churn these processed data.</description></item><item><title>Power of Open Data</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/07/power-of-open-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/07/power-of-open-data/</guid><description>Amidst the pandemic, tracking the daily case numbers from the government bulletin became a habit for us. For a small circle of friends involving 3-4 guys, it&amp;rsquo;s a routine to dissect the numbers and get meaning from the case number.
The distance between the decision-makers and us is more than the distance between Moon and Earth. Yet, we discuss as if to guide the entire state. The discussions usually raise some questions on the back story about the rise or fall of numbers.</description></item><item><title>Longreads with Kindle</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/05/longreads-with-kindle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/05/longreads-with-kindle/</guid><description>E-Commerce, eBooks, Prime Video &amp;amp; music even for some AWS. This is the list of items that my close surroundings say about Amazon&amp;rsquo;s domain. Kindle is mostly overlooked or not prominently known among people.
Kindle is a strange product from Amazon. Unlike its Video/music or retail site, Kindle appeals to a narrow circle - readers. Even among the readers, there is a split between ebook and physical book readers.
Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s the only hardware product from Amazon.</description></item><item><title>AWS Certified Solution Architect - for whom, why and how</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/04/aws-certified-solution-architect-for-whom-why-and-how/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 09:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/04/aws-certified-solution-architect-for-whom-why-and-how/</guid><description>Certifications are a waste of time. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable as I came across dumps (aka recent questions, question banks). Once you memorize the contents of the question bank, you can score cent percent. Memorise answers and recall them in the exam hall, score a pass mark - a common theme in schools and colleges. I went through it as there are no alternatives. But in the post-academic stage of life, I was hesitant to follow the same approach in office.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update 7 - Nov 10, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/11/weekly-update-7-nov-10-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 20:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/11/weekly-update-7-nov-10-2020/</guid><description>This is the 7th instalment of weekly update. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (November 10, 2020). This is 444 words long.
1. #USElection2020
Joe Biden (aka Amtrak Joe) is the president-elect, winning over the incumbent Donald J Trump. It&amp;rsquo;s been a huge drama right from the preparation to election till the vote counting. And, even now the counting is not over - the Senate &amp;amp; the House results are awaited.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update 6 - Nov 3, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/11/weekly-update-6-nov-3-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 20:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/11/weekly-update-6-nov-3-2020/</guid><description>This is the 6th instalment of weekly update. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (November 3, 2020). It&amp;rsquo;s been a month since I updated the page. To restart the habit, I&amp;rsquo;m keeping this short to cover only the COVID stats, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing interesting stuffs from the weekend.
Before wrapping it up lets touch on the most important event of the year.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update 5 - Sep 29, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-5-sep-29-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 19:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-5-sep-29-2020/</guid><description>This is the 5th instalment of weekly update. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (September 29, 2020). This is 759 words long.
Some interesting finds from the past week 1. What could an old TV could do? Breaking the Internet, may be.
Yes, the old TV took revenge on internet, in a village in Wales, UK. The story in the Register is worth a read, and could be valid post in r/Whatcouldgowrong</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update 4 - Sep 22, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-4-sep-22-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-4-sep-22-2020/</guid><description>This is the 4th instalment of weekly update. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (September 22, 2020). This is 757 words long.
Some interesting finds from the past week Big Bazaar Story
During college days, we visit Big Bazaar to have their ice cream. Ice cream connoisseurs may not agree, but for us, a small group of college kids who depend on pocket money for this occasional eat out, the Big Bazaar was the goto place.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update 3 - Sep 13, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-3-sep-13-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 21:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-3-sep-13-2020/</guid><description>This is the third instalment of weekly update. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (September 13, 2020). Word count at 800.
Some interesting items from the past week The AIIMS Story I happened to read about the founder of AIIMS - Rajkumari Amrit Kaur. This piece from Indian Express details on how she dreamt about an institute for medical higher education in India.</description></item><item><title>Unexpected outcome</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/unexpected-outcome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 19:47:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/unexpected-outcome/</guid><description>Here, I want to discuss about an unexpected outcome from interview. Contrary to the &amp;lsquo;rona times, I felt happy and contented.
The interview is usually a stressful affair. I usually prepare 100s of topics, then the interviewer will bombard me with 101st topic. Well, its just a déjà vu, nothing new with the session.
The interviewer was friendly and made me absolutely comfortable, there were no stress-inducing questions, all through the entire discussion.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update - Sep 6, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-sep-6-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 20:08:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/weekly-update-sep-6-2020/</guid><description>This is the second instalment of weekly update. Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (September 6, 2020).
Some interesting news the past week Monday&amp;rsquo;s news feed is filled with Chinese law that hurdles sale of TikTok to American entity. Chinese officials revised rules that govern the sale of certain kinds of technology to foreign buyers. The updated list includes data processing, speech and text recognition — the kind of tech that experts say is used by the popular short-form video app.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Update - Aug 30, 2020</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/08/weekly-update-aug-30-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 17:08:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/08/weekly-update-aug-30-2020/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the interesting things that I came across in between last Monday and today (August 30, 2020).
Positive News Apart from recoveries, I don&amp;rsquo;t see any positive news in the last week. As of 29th, the number of recovery is 2.712M, with total cases at 3.539M. Recovery rate @ 75+ Negative News As if the COVID-19 pandemic is not enough, the state of Assam is worst affected by flood in Brahmaputra river.</description></item><item><title>If you're approaching 20's or in early 20's</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/08/if-youre-approaching-20s-or-in-early-20s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 11:47:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/08/if-youre-approaching-20s-or-in-early-20s/</guid><description>In this write up, the hostel is used to indicate not only limited to the boarding school but also staying away from parents.
TL;DR You must live in a hostel.
All through these years since your arrival, you&amp;rsquo;ve a safety net named parents. They cleaned your shitty bums, they fed you with the food that are handpicked for your well-being, they were there when you tumbled down, they taught you how to walk, eat, pee et al.</description></item><item><title>One needn't be proud</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/07/one-neednt-be-proud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 23:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/07/one-neednt-be-proud/</guid><description>Social Media is a petri dish, culturing cultured and uncultured humans in real time. Based on your followers and taste you develop your own bubble, reinforce the bubble&amp;rsquo;s collective thought and at some point of time you&amp;rsquo;ll start believing it.
One way to not get lost in the rabbit hole is to think the collective thought (trending topic) is wrong and trying to justify it. Then I came across this &amp;lsquo;-pride&amp;rsquo; posts.</description></item><item><title>The return of Newsletters</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/the-return-of-newsletters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/the-return-of-newsletters/</guid><description>Emails became so much intertwined in our daily life. Whatever the internet service it be, eventually it comes to identifying you only through your email1. The newsletters used to be my source of information. I gradually unsubscribed to newsletters and marked the providers as important in my everyday feed of Twitter &amp;amp; Facebook.
There is a couple of first order effects,
I inadvertently started following so many users related to the news feeds The email inbox, once used to be zero inbox turned out to be filled with spams and filths Beyond First Order2</description></item><item><title>Essentially, they're non-essentials</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/essentially-theyre-non-essentials/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/essentially-theyre-non-essentials/</guid><description>The future generations must be viewing this as a biggest psychological experiment, worst case scenario and the inhumane practice to save humanity and much more. This is COVID-19 lockdown.
Lockdown was imposed on March 25th 2020. Being a social animal, we went through a lot. The ill effects of lockdown ranges from anxiety induced due to potential job loss - historic unemployment rate, potential downturn of investments in coming years, struggling to keep up with daily work-from-home with it&amp;rsquo;s own challenges.</description></item><item><title>A curious question on reading?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/a-curious-question-on-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 11:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/a-curious-question-on-reading/</guid><description>My SO asked a curious question. I froze, like a Windows XP machine, couldn&amp;rsquo;t answer then. After the incident, for several nights, the question ran through in my head to decipher the answer.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with little about me . I like to read books. As of today, reading is one of the hobby for me. For her, reading is a boring chore, like majority around me.
The question was simple and on to the point.</description></item><item><title>A lost relationship</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/a-lost-relationship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/a-lost-relationship/</guid><description>The relationship lasted for 2 years, 3 months, 11 days. Barring restroom moments, we were together all the time. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about my Pixel 2, which has provided me a wonderful experience on any electronics gadget that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever owned.
There are few things, worth mentioning here, both positive &amp;amp; negative.
Software-hardware, made for each other - Even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t used any flagship mobile till then, I feel P2 showed me how it feels when OS is made for hardware.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19: Political change on the cards?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/covid-19-political-change-on-the-cards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:10:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/covid-19-political-change-on-the-cards/</guid><description>The outbreak is here. Turned into Pandemic, spreading across geographies without much of obstacles. The impact is felt in so many domains, from hospitals to hospitality, from tourism industry to ride-sharing. Governments are scrambling to slow down its spread. The corporates are equipping employees with work-from-home options. Unorganized sector is going for a toss. So, how could the COVID-19 affect the governing bodies?
Late 2010s and the raise of Nationalists The Nationalists or Conservatives or Right wingers are in raise in the 2nd half of 2010s, across the world.</description></item><item><title>Couple of things that went unnoticed</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/couple-of-things-that-went-unnoticed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:01:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/couple-of-things-that-went-unnoticed/</guid><description>Last July marks the Quadrennial year working in an MNC. These years had taught me several valuable lessons. Learnt either from first-hand experience or learning from others action. What I learnt is that our fundamentals are flawed as several important things are not taught at young age.
There are 2 important things that must be included in curriculum.
Career vs. Job : In earlier generation, its pride to be working with an employer for long duration (say, in terms years or decades).</description></item><item><title>Shouldn’t there be some regulation – road side shops</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/shouldnt-there-be-some-regulation-road-side-shops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/shouldnt-there-be-some-regulation-road-side-shops/</guid><description>Waking up at the morning, after finishing morning-activities I noticed there was no water. I should have checked the water can in the night. Duh!! Should have called the water can vendor if I reached home came earlier. He did delivered the cans after a call and waiting for a hour.
Breakfast time. Rushed out to road-side eatery. While waiting for dishes to be prepared, had conversation with the owner-cum-server, came to know that the continuous rain for 3 days the last week has affected their business.</description></item><item><title>Striving with Contextual speakers</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/striving-with-contextual-speakers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/striving-with-contextual-speakers/</guid><description>Are you connected to WiFi?, isn’t it slow?”
First part of above sentence is objectively denotes ‘WiFi’. The second part contextually denotes ‘WiFi’ through the word – ‘it’.
According Merriam-Webster, Context is defined as,
The parts of a discourse that surround a word or passage and can throw light on its meaning
Every tech giant is boasting that their digital assistants can understand our contextual conversation. Indeed it is a big step for machines to understand our natural speech.</description></item><item><title>Working with Raspberry Pi files</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/working-with-raspberry-pi-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/working-with-raspberry-pi-files/</guid><description>Some reference on how to connect to a Raspberry Pi running in the same LAN network.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Raspberry Pi running in home, for last 10 months. Until a month ago, the sole purpose of the RPi is to filter off the ads using Pi-hole1, then a speed test module was scheduled to run on it. By the setup, the speedtest-cli runs every 10 mins and fetches internet into csv file.</description></item><item><title>Comparison of various HDFS file formats</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/02/comparison-of-various-hdfs-file-formats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/02/comparison-of-various-hdfs-file-formats/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Big data since 2017. As I&amp;rsquo;m from data warehousing background, it was easier for me to understand what&amp;rsquo;s what, and build an analogy between DWH &amp;amp; big data frameworks. However, the various file formats used in HDFS always caught me off guard.
In DWH, I never considered how the files are stored in DB, it&amp;rsquo;s managed by the database, maybe DBA might know how its done at the backend, as a DB developer it never bothered me.</description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-2/</guid><description>This is 2nd installment of the story. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to arrange beautiful photos of the last decade. The photos are all captured by me.
The foggy view of training center on a December morning. The first time I had a taste of resort-like place. 2011 - The Training Days The Kevin Mitnick replied and followed me, after a tweet about Ghost in the Wires Kevin Mitnick follows me This was one only outreach programme that I took part in.</description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 1</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 14:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-1/</guid><description>The 2010&amp;rsquo;s was my 20&amp;rsquo;s. I was in the middle of under graduate course when the decade begun. An average engineering graduate who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what engineering really was or what&amp;rsquo;s the future is offering. The end of year marks the recruitment to my current employer. Yes right, I&amp;rsquo;m with the employer for almost a decade.
IIRC 13k was my 1st my first salary. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall how I spent it, guess gave it to my mom.</description></item><item><title>The Guinea Pig Generation</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/12/the-guinea-pig-generation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 21:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/12/the-guinea-pig-generation/</guid><description>The generation born between 1985-95 has more or less seen the technology evolution from the fron seat. The advent of internet, landline giving up its place to mobile phones, more desk jobs than the labour intensive work. Through this journey, the lifestyle got altered to a large extent. Some of the changes are just an improvemnt to our life, while some or controversial in nature. I call them controversial as harmful effects are neither proved nor denied by scientific community.</description></item><item><title>PyConIndia 2019</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</guid><description>My primary source of Python and Python related news was/is Python podcast, since 2016. In 2018, I came to know about Pycon taking place in Cleveland, OH. Dan Bader&amp;rsquo;s vlog on PyCon &amp;lsquo;18 was another pull factor towards the PyCon. Due to the ticket pricing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to it. In H2 of 2018, I returned to India, and was looking forward to attend PyConIndia, which should be affordable.</description></item><item><title>Oxidation 2 - Variables, Shadowing</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-2-variables-shadowing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-2-variables-shadowing/</guid><description>Variables
In Python, the variables are assigned with the type based on the content.
string_variable = &amp;#39;some text&amp;#39; int_variable = 33 print(type(string_variable), type(int_variable)) And, these variables are allowed to change in a program.
In Rust, the variables can either be mutable or immutable. By default, the variables are immutable.
Mutable - Values are allowed to change Immutable - Values are not allowed to change
fn main(){letdefault_variable=2;println!(&amp;#34;The value in default_variable is {}&amp;#34;,{default_variable});default_variable=3;//Here, the code will fail.</description></item><item><title>Oxidation 1 - Cargo, Rustdoc</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-1-cargo-rustdoc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-1-cargo-rustdoc/</guid><description>What is rustup, rustc &amp;amp; rustdoc ?
rustup- Used to update the latest Rust version. rustc filename.rs - Used to compile rust source code. rustdoc - Rust documentation is generated from this command. This can generate documentation from markdown files. Also, it show the Rustbook opens in browser when called as rustup docs
Project initialization After installing Rust, we should initialize a project using Cargo cargo init project_path - This will create a project folder of below file structure.</description></item><item><title>What makes Rust interesting?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/what-makes-rust-interesting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/what-makes-rust-interesting/</guid><description>Podcasts. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got introduced to the Rust language.
In one of the PythonBytes episode I heard about the PyOxidizer for the first time. Basically, it uses Rust to bundle Python code into an executable code. There is already quite a number of modules to convert code into an executable file. According to Michael Kennedy, the Git repo is so active, that made me to explore what the PyOxidizer is made of.</description></item><item><title>Yes, humanity exists</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/yes-humanity-exists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/yes-humanity-exists/</guid><description>The social media is made of several bubbles. The bubbles, each of us build around us, with like minded people. With the bubble is well constructed, we live and slowly start believing it is the reflection of the actual world.
This is what happened to me in recent times. There is some negative news keep getting shared to me via whatsapp, twitter or facebook. The negativity comes in the form of political corruption to pedophilia.</description></item><item><title>Podcast listening 101</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/podcast-listening-101/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/podcast-listening-101/</guid><description>Podcast is a audio show, could be anythingranging from interviews to discussions to story telling. The Podcasts became a thing with the iPods. Even the term itself derived from the Apple&amp;rsquo;s gadget. Off late, with the arrival of 3rd party apps, more people from Android are attracted, along with the Apple users.
In Apple, iTunes enables us to listen to Podcast. Google released their own app very recently and the customization is very limited.</description></item><item><title>Fight against Climate Change is not getting traction - Why?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/fight-against-climate-change-is-not-getting-traction-why/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 11:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/fight-against-climate-change-is-not-getting-traction-why/</guid><description>We all know the Climate change is real and happening now. This is a threat to the Human species. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a threat to the species not the entire planet. Why not we as a species cannot survive this? The nature will adapt to the changes. But, the new earth will no way close to the one we have now. Also, we got deviated from the natural evolution. Our life became sophisticated, without the necessary infrastructure we will kill ourself in the name of depression.</description></item><item><title>No more Ad breaks - thanks Pi-hole</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/no-more-ad-breaks-thanks-pi-hole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 20:12:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/no-more-ad-breaks-thanks-pi-hole/</guid><description>While browsing through Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s sub in Reddit, I came across Pi-hole.
Pi-hole is an interesting project, claims to be black hole of Ads. I guess the pi in the name refers to Raspberry Pi. As my Pi3 was lying in the corner unused, I went for the Pi-hole installation. Before continuing further on the experience, we need to discuss why the ads are bothering?
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with ads? I agree the ads are the revenue source of websites.</description></item><item><title>First serious project that has some rational application</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/first-serious-project-that-has-some-rational-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 23:15:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/first-serious-project-that-has-some-rational-application/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working in a corporate firm which employs 100K+ employees. As do with any organization of such a magnitude, there are certain rules &amp;amp; policies which cannot be breached. In most of the occasions, the policies really help us navigate without much of the issue. Yet, there are situations which impedes our progress.
The impedement I felt was merging PDF files. What&amp;rsquo;s there to worry about, you may wonder. In our org, we have some version of Adobe Reader to view PDFs.</description></item><item><title>Starting with Jekyll</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/starting-with-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 22:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/starting-with-jekyll/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s cool to have a personal website. As a novice, where to start? The cheapest, practical and programmatic option is Github Pages
Cheapest - Free to use GH Pages. You may not get a dedicated domain, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a name.github.io
Practical - You can go for blogger or wordPress for writing a blog post. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get to experience the nitty-gritty involved with running an actual website.
Programmatic - Once you started programming, it will be intriguing to learn something new.</description></item><item><title>EVMs should be avoided for Indian elections - Why?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/evms-should-be-avoided-for-indian-elections-why/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/evms-should-be-avoided-for-indian-elections-why/</guid><description>As a country, 1990&amp;rsquo;s are changing times for India. The nation saw some of the interesting transformations, which would be an unimaginable tale even a decade earlier for Geo-political experts. The changes ranges from Economic stance of the country to opening up to private cable channels to introduction of Internet to the masses (the snail-paced dial-ups).
The election commission too hopped into the transformation train. From the conventional paper based ballot, the Electronic Voting Machines were introduced.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the site!</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/welcome-to-the-site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 19:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/welcome-to-the-site/</guid><description>This is a new site built on Jekyll, hosted on GitHub.
I came across the GitHub Pages. As the flow looks intriguing, I&amp;rsquo;m trying out this. As a blogger I tried out Wordpress, Blogspot and Medium. The interest to compose a post fizzles out very often. However, I&amp;rsquo;m trying harder to reverse the trend.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes.</description></item><item><title>Final frontier for AI could be decoding Sarcasm</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/06/final-frontier-for-ai-could-be-decoding-sarcasm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 20:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/06/final-frontier-for-ai-could-be-decoding-sarcasm/</guid><description>Sarcasm, according to Google is “ the use of irony to mock or convey contempt”. Interpreting it could be final frontier for AI.
Understanding Sarcastic line is a complex process. Depends on lots of variables — context, body language, tone modulation and so on. To be fair there is not proper/scientific way to decode sarcasm. To add to it, degree of closeness is (kinda) proportional to complexity of sarcasm.
In one of the scene Deadpool 2 movie, the lead actor was questioned who he is.</description></item><item><title>What is farming — Biz or Charity?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/02/what-is-farming-biz-or-charity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 21:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/02/what-is-farming-biz-or-charity/</guid><description>Occupation (for-profit) or welfare/charity (non-profit)?
This is the question which started a long conversation with my friend over Whatsapp.
Why does it matter? Everything depends on the answer. If it’s Occupation, you can tax them for the revenue, likewise you can insure them so they can land safe in times of tragedy. Or if its a welfare, government can take it or some NGOs can chip in with funding from benevolent sponsors.</description></item><item><title>Democracy, a silver bullet?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2017/05/democracy-a-silver-bullet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2017/05/democracy-a-silver-bullet/</guid><description>I’m a big fan of Democratic government. Went to war, in cyber world, with my friends whenever they say Saudi Arabia/China style of government is better than D-government. I’m pro-democracy because I believe in free will of humans.
So far, every dictator has ruled the people, crushed the basic rights in the name of religion, communism, socialism et al. We are not animals to be herded by some dictator. On the other end of spectrum, we have democracy.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/now/</guid><description>What am I doing now? Reading Hannibal by Thomas Harris</description></item></channel></rss>