<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Delighted on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/delighted/</link><description>Recent content in Delighted on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:08:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/delighted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unexpected outcome</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/unexpected-outcome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 19:47:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/unexpected-outcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here, I want to discuss about an unexpected outcome from interview. Contrary to the &amp;lsquo;rona times, I felt happy and contented.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The interview is usually a stressful affair. I usually prepare &lt;em>100s&lt;/em> of topics, then the interviewer will bombard me with &lt;em>101&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup>&lt;/em> topic. Well, its just a déjà vu, nothing new with the session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The interviewer was friendly and made me absolutely comfortable, there were no stress-inducing questions, all through the entire discussion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yes, humanity exists</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/yes-humanity-exists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/yes-humanity-exists/</guid><description>&lt;p>The social media is made of several bubbles. The bubbles, each of us build around us, with like minded people. With the bubble is well constructed, we live and slowly start believing it is the reflection of the actual world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what happened to me in recent times. There is some negative news keep getting shared to me via whatsapp, twitter or facebook. The negativity comes in the form of political corruption to pedophilia. Slowly and steadily I started believing we are living in place where humanity turned extinct.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>