<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/event/</link><description>Recent content in Event on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:41:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Event Update: M2W Conclave 2.0</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This is about an event or a gathering around the theme of personal finance. The crowd gathered is through the Youtube channel - Muthaleetukalam (முதலீட்டுக்களம்) translates to &lt;em>&amp;lsquo;Investment sector&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>, &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=ta&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;text=%E0%AE%AE%E0%AF%81%E0%AE%A4%E0%AE%B2%E0%AF%80%E0%AE%9F%E0%AF%8D%E0%AE%9F%E0%AF%81%E0%AE%95%E0%AF%8D%E0%AE%95%E0%AE%B3%E0%AE%AE%E0%AF%8D&amp;amp;op=translate">thanks Google&lt;/a>. This is coordinated by iThought Wealth&amp;rsquo;s Shyam Shekhar through his &lt;a href="https://milestones2wealth.com/">milestones2wealth&lt;/a>, a portal to make &lt;em>Making
Small Investors THINK BIG!&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;style>
div.rightBox {
 position: absolute;
 right: 0;
 width: 230px;
 height: 250px;
 border: 3px solid grey;
}

&lt;/style>
&lt;!-- The history -->
&lt;h1 id="my-pov">My PoV&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I started following the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@muthaleetukalam">channel&lt;/a> during the lockdown, just like million other self-proclaimed investors. The channel is not for trader/speculator/FnO players or gamblers. The videos pops up everyday since the lockdown times. The primary theme is investor behavior, or current events with respect of finance or economics. Some day special guests gets featured, to share their experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Event Update: Consecration</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/event-update-consecration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/event-update-consecration/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m in the midway between an atheist, agnostic and a religious person. My particiaption in events based out of religious tradition, is almost always doubtful. Yet, I was part of this community gathering, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- What it is and when? -->
&lt;p>When a temple gets built, it deserves sequence of rituals that adds spiritual and religious power to the deity living in the temple. As it is a belief based system, logical questioing doesn&amp;rsquo;t end well. The event took place on August 17-19, 2024.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyConIndia 2019</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>My primary source of Python and Python related news was/is &lt;a href="https://talkpython.fm">Python podcast&lt;/a>, since 2016. In 2018, I came to know about Pycon taking place in Cleveland, OH. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zDVlqeOT2XY&amp;amp;list=PLP8GkvaIxJP281FqVlJBgHGyMRvP9NtYN">Dan Bader&amp;rsquo;s vlog on PyCon &amp;lsquo;18&lt;/a> was another pull factor towards the PyCon. Due to the ticket pricing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to it. In H2 of 2018, I returned to India, and was looking forward to attend PyConIndia, which should be affordable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyConIndia &amp;lsquo;19 is taking place in Chennai, which happened to be my second home. There can&amp;rsquo;t be anymore reason to miss the conference. The ticket booking opened for PyConIndia on one fine day. Then I did booked a ticket, sadly couldn&amp;rsquo;t book the early bird ticket.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>