<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2025 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2025/</link><description>Recent content in 2025 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 11:38:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 Years of Data, Deadlines and Growth</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/04/3-years-of-data-deadlines-and-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/04/3-years-of-data-deadlines-and-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the blogs for some years now. I came across the annual reviews on the FreeFinCal site; it&amp;rsquo;s a shame I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall the exact year. My guess would be somewhere between 2018 and 2020.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the pandemic, I started subscribing to the Substacks. I noticed almost everyone who is regularly writing is reviewing the annual performance. And I always wanted to write one for myself. The birthdays, New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eves, and financial year-end—all of them provided a chance to write. All these days were an opportunity to sit down and look back at what has happened.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IPL: Ways to see beyond Scoreboard</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/03/ipl-ways-to-see-beyond-scoreboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/03/ipl-ways-to-see-beyond-scoreboard/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data visualization is one field that has kept me captivated for some time now. The graphics published in sites like FT, Reuters, or NYT made me wonder why I don&amp;rsquo;t spend time on the skill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The good volume and variety of data that is available is available all the time. Share market—daily; IPL—yearly. I find each of the cricket matches, no matter if they are Test, ODI, or T20, generates so much data. I tried once with the ODI World Cup; it&amp;rsquo;s not at all a good one. It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of years, and I&amp;rsquo;m planning to visualize this IPL. My preferred tool is D3JS, and even with that, I&amp;rsquo;m limited to a few shapes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>