<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Team Work on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/team-work/</link><description>Recent content in Team Work on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:10:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/team-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learnings from working with external teams</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the recent change in the role from data engineer to &lt;a href="https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/">lead data engineer&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m regularly interacting with different teams, both upstream and downstream. It had become routine to have meetings with the counterparties to understand their difficulties. After all, we are a tree but a part of a forest.  &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diversity-factor">Diversity factor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It might annoy us to hear about diversity from the MNCs again and again. However, for the proper functioning of the organization, it is essential to have associates from various backgrounds. This plurality ensures different ideas and approaches to a problem, which in turn gives the authorities the ability to compare and pick a better, more efficient solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflections on recent changes in work place</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last few weeks have been tough. The problem seems to originate from all three avenues: life, work, and the social circle. My child is demanding that I play with her more regularly and for more time. By size, my social circle is small. I feel the size further shrinks due to my inability to speak or interact with my close friends. Even though the friends usually accept the fact that life is getting busier, the crack appears nonetheless.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>