<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reading on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Reading on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:29:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fumbling 145 days long kindle reading streak</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</guid><description>&lt;p>If my memory serves right, Snapchat popularised the &lt;em>streak&lt;/em> phenomena. Later on, the amount popularity and stickiness it creates among the user, many companies jumped on the band wagon - fitness trackers, calories trackers and many more. What the streak does is it creates a habit among the users and make them to use the particular service on daily basis. Also, it creates a sense of pride with the longer streak on has.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Longreads with Kindle</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/05/longreads-with-kindle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/05/longreads-with-kindle/</guid><description>&lt;p>E-Commerce, eBooks, Prime Video &amp;amp; music even for some AWS. This is the list of items that my close surroundings say about Amazon&amp;rsquo;s domain. Kindle is mostly overlooked or not prominently known among people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kindle is a strange product from Amazon. Unlike its Video/music or retail site, Kindle appeals to a narrow circle - readers. Even among the readers, there is a &lt;a href="https://lifehacker.com/which-is-better-ebooks-or-paper-books-1625005600">split&lt;/a> between ebook and physical book readers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s the only hardware product from Amazon. The hardware is not some cheap plastic. The device boasts a solid design, handy to carry around, easier to handle in a single hand. The battery is one of the key factors, once fully charged the device runs for weeks.
.Secondly, unlike other products Kindle helps us to build a constructive habit - reading. Third, once you acquire Kindle you can circumvent Amazon entirely and no need to pay. The hardware superiority and goodness of reading have been covered by so many blogs. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how I&amp;rsquo;m using Kindle to use Kindle.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>