<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2021/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 23:06:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yet another tech CEO of Indian origin</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/11/yet-another-tech-ceo-of-indian-origin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 20:06:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/11/yet-another-tech-ceo-of-indian-origin/</guid><description>&lt;p>From co-founder to CEO, Jack Dorsey was carrying Twitter&amp;rsquo;s identity for sometime now. He is not without controversies. Twitter and Facebook came to prominence on somewhat same time. Yet, Facebook became a cash-rich poster boy among the social media, Twitter lagging behind Facebook, unclear how to monetize the Twitter as a product. As a CEO, he was blamed for being CEO on Square and not concentrating on Twitter.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">+ Fun fact: Argawal joins the growing ranks of powerful US tech executives of Indian descent. Google, Microsoft, Adobe, IBM, Palo Alto Networks, and now Twitter are all run by people who grew up in India.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A backend dev's journey into JS world - Part I</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 13:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use SQL and Python to earn my bread. Being an ETL developer turned Data Engineer, my work is to fetch data from different sources, cleaning it, and making it consumption ready before storing it in some storage space - database, S3 et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s amusing to know that someone will be consuming this data and pull insights from it like a magician pulling a rabbit off his hat. The reporting tools were the go-to place to churn these processed data. The decision-makers use the reports generated by these tools. The reports are mostly limited to tables, bar, line, or pie charts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power of Open Data</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/07/power-of-open-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/07/power-of-open-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amidst the pandemic, tracking the daily case numbers from the government bulletin became a habit for us. For a small circle of friends involving 3-4 guys, it&amp;rsquo;s a routine to dissect the numbers and get meaning from the case number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The distance between the decision-makers and us is more than the distance between Moon and Earth. Yet, we discuss as if to guide the entire state. The discussions usually raise some questions on the back story about the rise or fall of numbers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Longreads with Kindle</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/05/longreads-with-kindle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 21:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/05/longreads-with-kindle/</guid><description>&lt;p>E-Commerce, eBooks, Prime Video &amp;amp; music even for some AWS. This is the list of items that my close surroundings say about Amazon&amp;rsquo;s domain. Kindle is mostly overlooked or not prominently known among people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kindle is a strange product from Amazon. Unlike its Video/music or retail site, Kindle appeals to a narrow circle - readers. Even among the readers, there is a &lt;a href="https://lifehacker.com/which-is-better-ebooks-or-paper-books-1625005600">split&lt;/a> between ebook and physical book readers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s the only hardware product from Amazon. The hardware is not some cheap plastic. The device boasts a solid design, handy to carry around, easier to handle in a single hand. The battery is one of the key factors, once fully charged the device runs for weeks.
.Secondly, unlike other products Kindle helps us to build a constructive habit - reading. Third, once you acquire Kindle you can circumvent Amazon entirely and no need to pay. The hardware superiority and goodness of reading have been covered by so many blogs. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how I&amp;rsquo;m using Kindle to use Kindle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Certified Solution Architect - for whom, why and how</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/04/aws-certified-solution-architect-for-whom-why-and-how/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 09:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/04/aws-certified-solution-architect-for-whom-why-and-how/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Certifications are a waste of time&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable as I came across dumps (aka recent questions, question banks). Once you memorize the contents of the question bank, you can score cent percent. &lt;em>Memorise answers and recall them in the exam hall, score a pass mark&lt;/em> - a common theme in schools and colleges. I went through it as there are no alternatives. But in the post-academic stage of life, I was hesitant to follow the same approach in office. My point was simple,&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>