<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technical on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/technical/</link><description>Recent content in technical on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:22:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrated to blogdown</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/10/migrated-to-blogdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/10/migrated-to-blogdown/</guid><description>I was using Hugo for static site generation with Beautiful Hugo as a theme. The theme is known for its balancing act between simplicity and proseness for a blog. With Hugo its a fast act to creating and publishing the contents.
It was all good until I wanted to embed a HTML page. iFrame is always there but including the charts, especially interactive ones generated as HTML is tough to embed in the post (at least for me).</description></item><item><title>How much Income Tax Are We Paying?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/how-much-income-tax-are-we-paying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 08:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/how-much-income-tax-are-we-paying/</guid><description>During the last months of every financial year, there is a tradition, a custom to keep ourselves sane - ranting on tax that we suffered through the year, and any returns we can expect from the taxmen.
In one of the ranting sessions, we had an interesting conversation.
How much tax are we paying?.
What is so interesting?
The tax must be either 25% (new regime) or 30% (old regime).</description></item><item><title>Hugo Site Deployment Using Github Actions</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/hugo-site-deployment-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 19:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/hugo-site-deployment-using-github-actions/</guid><description>This is a small write up about setting up GitHub Actions to deploy Hugo site.
Table of content How I was deploying it earlier? What was the problem there? How does the GitHub Actions helps us here? How I was deploying it earlier? I used to have 2 commits for any changes.
Changes to the posts HTML documents generated through hugo command What was the problem there?</description></item><item><title>A backend dev's journey into JS world - Part I</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 13:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</guid><description>I use SQL and Python to earn my bread. Being an ETL developer turned Data Engineer, my work is to fetch data from different sources, cleaning it, and making it consumption ready before storing it in some storage space - database, S3 et al.
It&amp;rsquo;s amusing to know that someone will be consuming this data and pull insights from it like a magician pulling a rabbit off his hat. The reporting tools were the go-to place to churn these processed data.</description></item><item><title>Working with Raspberry Pi files</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/working-with-raspberry-pi-files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/working-with-raspberry-pi-files/</guid><description>Some reference on how to connect to a Raspberry Pi running in the same LAN network.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Raspberry Pi running in home, for last 10 months. Until a month ago, the sole purpose of the RPi is to filter off the ads using Pi-hole1, then a speed test module was scheduled to run on it. By the setup, the speedtest-cli runs every 10 mins and fetches internet into csv file.</description></item><item><title>Comparison of various HDFS file formats</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/02/comparison-of-various-hdfs-file-formats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/02/comparison-of-various-hdfs-file-formats/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Big data since 2017. As I&amp;rsquo;m from data warehousing background, it was easier for me to understand what&amp;rsquo;s what, and build an analogy between DWH &amp;amp; big data frameworks. However, the various file formats used in HDFS always caught me off guard.
In DWH, I never considered how the files are stored in DB, it&amp;rsquo;s managed by the database, maybe DBA might know how its done at the backend, as a DB developer it never bothered me.</description></item><item><title>Oxidation 2 - Variables, Shadowing</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-2-variables-shadowing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-2-variables-shadowing/</guid><description>Variables
In Python, the variables are assigned with the type based on the content.
string_variable = &amp;#39;some text&amp;#39; int_variable = 33 print(type(string_variable), type(int_variable)) And, these variables are allowed to change in a program.
In Rust, the variables can either be mutable or immutable. By default, the variables are immutable.
Mutable - Values are allowed to change Immutable - Values are not allowed to change
fn main(){letdefault_variable=2;println!(&amp;#34;The value in default_variable is {}&amp;#34;,{default_variable});default_variable=3;//Here, the code will fail.</description></item><item><title>Oxidation 1 - Cargo, Rustdoc</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-1-cargo-rustdoc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/oxidation-1-cargo-rustdoc/</guid><description>What is rustup, rustc &amp;amp; rustdoc ?
rustup- Used to update the latest Rust version. rustc filename.rs - Used to compile rust source code. rustdoc - Rust documentation is generated from this command. This can generate documentation from markdown files. Also, it show the Rustbook opens in browser when called as rustup docs
Project initialization After installing Rust, we should initialize a project using Cargo cargo init project_path - This will create a project folder of below file structure.</description></item><item><title>What makes Rust interesting?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/what-makes-rust-interesting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/what-makes-rust-interesting/</guid><description>Podcasts. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got introduced to the Rust language.
In one of the PythonBytes episode I heard about the PyOxidizer for the first time. Basically, it uses Rust to bundle Python code into an executable code. There is already quite a number of modules to convert code into an executable file. According to Michael Kennedy, the Git repo is so active, that made me to explore what the PyOxidizer is made of.</description></item><item><title>No more Ad breaks - thanks Pi-hole</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/no-more-ad-breaks-thanks-pi-hole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 20:12:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/no-more-ad-breaks-thanks-pi-hole/</guid><description>While browsing through Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s sub in Reddit, I came across Pi-hole.
Pi-hole is an interesting project, claims to be black hole of Ads. I guess the pi in the name refers to Raspberry Pi. As my Pi3 was lying in the corner unused, I went for the Pi-hole installation. Before continuing further on the experience, we need to discuss why the ads are bothering?
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with ads? I agree the ads are the revenue source of websites.</description></item><item><title>First serious project that has some rational application</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/first-serious-project-that-has-some-rational-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 23:15:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/first-serious-project-that-has-some-rational-application/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working in a corporate firm which employs 100K+ employees. As do with any organization of such a magnitude, there are certain rules &amp;amp; policies which cannot be breached. In most of the occasions, the policies really help us navigate without much of the issue. Yet, there are situations which impedes our progress.
The impedement I felt was merging PDF files. What&amp;rsquo;s there to worry about, you may wonder. In our org, we have some version of Adobe Reader to view PDFs.</description></item><item><title>Starting with Jekyll</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/starting-with-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 22:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/starting-with-jekyll/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s cool to have a personal website. As a novice, where to start? The cheapest, practical and programmatic option is Github Pages
Cheapest - Free to use GH Pages. You may not get a dedicated domain, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a name.github.io
Practical - You can go for blogger or wordPress for writing a blog post. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get to experience the nitty-gritty involved with running an actual website.
Programmatic - Once you started programming, it will be intriguing to learn something new.</description></item></channel></rss>