<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experience on Dheepak's blog</title><link>/categories/experience/</link><description>Recent content in Experience on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 19:47:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unexpected outcome</title><link>/post/2020-09-08-delighted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 19:47:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-09-08-delighted/</guid><description>Here, I want to discuss about an unexpected outcome from interview. Contrary to the &amp;lsquo;rona times, I felt happy and contented.
The interview is usually a stressful affair. I usually prepare 100s of topics, then the interviewer will bombard me with 101st topic. Well, its just a déjà vu, nothing new with the session.
The interviewer was friendly and made me absolutely comfortable, there were no stress-inducing questions, all through the entire discussion.</description></item><item><title>A lost relationship</title><link>/post/2020-04-12-a-lost-relatioship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-04-12-a-lost-relatioship/</guid><description>The relationship lasted for 2 years, 3 months, 11 days. Barring restroom moments, we were together all the time. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about my Pixel 2, which has provided me a wonderful experience on any electronics gadget that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever owned.
There are few things, worth mentioning here, both positive &amp;amp; negative.
Software-hardware, made for each other - Even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t used any flagship mobile till then, I feel P2 showed me how it feels when OS is made for hardware.</description></item><item><title>Striving with Contextual speakers</title><link>/post/2020-04-08-contextual-speakers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-04-08-contextual-speakers/</guid><description>Are you connected to WiFi?, isn’t it slow?”
First part of above sentence is objectively denotes ‘WiFi’. The second part contextually denotes ‘WiFi’ through the word – ‘it’.
According Merriam-Webster, Context is defined as,
The parts of a discourse that surround a word or passage and can throw light on its meaning
Every tech giant is boasting that their digital assistants can understand our contextual conversation. Indeed it is a big step for machines to understand our natural speech.</description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 1</title><link>/post/2020-01-05-the-last-decade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 14:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-01-05-the-last-decade/</guid><description>The 2010&amp;rsquo;s was my 20&amp;rsquo;s. I was in the middle of under graduate course when the decade begun. An average engineering graduate who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what engineering really was or what&amp;rsquo;s the future is offering. The end of year marks the recruitment to my current employer. Yes right, I&amp;rsquo;m with the employer for almost a decade.
IIRC 13k was my 1stmy first salary. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall how I spent it, guess gave it to my mom.</description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 2</title><link>/post/2020-01-06-the-2010s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 14:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-01-06-the-2010s-part-2/</guid><description>This is 2ndinstallment of the story. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to arrange beautiful photos of the last decade. The photos are all captured by me.
The foggy view of training center on a December morning. The first time I had a taste of resort-like place. 2011 - The Training Days The Kevin Mitnick replied and followed me, after a tweet about Ghost in the Wires Kevin Mitnick follows me This was one only outreach programme that I took part in.</description></item><item><title>PyConIndia 2019</title><link>/post/2019-10-13-pycon-india-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2019-10-13-pycon-india-2019/</guid><description>My primary source of Python and Python related news was/is Python podcast, since 2016. In 2018, I came to know about Pycon taking place in Cleveland, OH. Dan Bader&amp;rsquo;s vlog on PyCon &amp;lsquo;18 was another pull factor towards the PyCon. Due to the ticket pricing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to it. In H2 of 2018, I returned to India, and was looking forward to attend PyConIndia, which should be affordable.</description></item><item><title>Yes, humanity exists</title><link>/post/2019-07-22-humanity-exists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2019-07-22-humanity-exists/</guid><description>The social media is made of several bubbles. The bubbles, each of us build around us, with like minded people. With the bubble is well constructed, we live and slowly start believing it is the reflection of the actual world.
This is what happened to me in recent times. There is some negative news keep getting shared to me via whatsapp, twitter or facebook. The negativity comes in the form of political corruption to pedophilia.</description></item><item><title>Podcast listening 101</title><link>/post/2019-07-07-podcast-101/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2019-07-07-podcast-101/</guid><description>Podcast is a audio show, could be anythingranging from interviews to discussions to story telling. The Podcasts became a thing with the iPods. Even the term itself derived from the Apple&amp;rsquo;s gadget. Off late, with the arrival of 3rdparty apps, more people from Android are attracted, along with the Apple users.
In Apple, iTunes enables us to listen to Podcast. Google released their own app very recently and the customization is very limited.</description></item></channel></rss>