<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2023/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fumbling 145 days long kindle reading streak</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</guid><description>If my memory serves right, Snapchat popularised the streak phenomena. Later on, the amount popularity and stickiness it creates among the user, many companies jumped on the band wagon - fitness trackers, calories trackers and many more. What the streak does is it creates a habit among the users and make them to use the particular service on daily basis. Also, it creates a sense of pride with the longer streak on has.</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3 - v3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v3/</guid><description>This is a follow up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post on same name.
What&amp;rsquo;s new? Tooltip - Earlier, we were employing the browser&amp;rsquo;s native tooltip. With this update we have customised tooltip with publish date and categories along with the title of post. Transitions - On hovering the circles turns green and tooltip pops up. .tooltip { position: absolute; font-family: monospace; pointer-events: none; background: silver; color: black; /* width: 400px; */ text-align: left; border-radius: 6px; padding: 5px 5px; left: 50%; margin-left: -60px; z-index: 1; } .</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3 - v2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/05/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/05/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v2/</guid><description>This is a follow up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post on same name.
There are few changes made to the chart.
Today marker: Instead of drawing a full line for the current year, we are allowing the line to grow with passing day. This is a major change. Transition: The trasnition effects are the major change here. Ironically, the amount of code change is minimum - tbh addition of 2 lines is all that&amp;rsquo;s needed.</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/</guid><description>This is an attempt to recreate the earlier created blog post through D3js.
I&amp;rsquo;m more of backend developer, working predominantly in Python + SQL. But, trying out JS is long time wish, which got fufilled through a Udemy course and some good imspiration.
The visuals can be improved vastly and can add few more options. But this post is to show the progress. Also, this is an attempt to conform that D3JS output can be hosted on our static site.</description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</guid><description>Once in a while we stumble into something interesting while we are not looking for it. This is a post on how I came across a chart while going through an online course, the experience in replicating the chart, the lessons I learnt.
The instructor of the course - Course: Data Visualization Fundamentals and Best Practices by ObservableHQ. While going through his website I found this interesting chart - Blog Calendar.</description></item><item><title>Multiple roles of a man</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</guid><description>The 30s are tricky period. Till 20s you can survive with a student or young earner tag. In the late 20s, you experience what the freedom is. And, when you start feeling you can do whatever you can and reach wherever you want to in life. Now you&amp;rsquo;re in your 30s and most likely you got punched at your face.
Why 30s are so tough A simple answer is roles that each person plays.</description></item><item><title>API, Configurations &amp; Database operation</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/api-configurations-database-operation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/api-configurations-database-operation/</guid><description>Right now the project focuses on creating dashboard for Mutual funds, and gradually adding other investement vehicles viz stocks, PPF, and EPF.
Fetching NAVs To track the mutual funds, we come across an API by Yuvaraj Loganathan - MFAPI. Thank you, Yuvaraj. The API gets updated on daily basis and free to access (as in free beer). For our project, which is not intended for any financial gain, this api is the right fit.</description></item><item><title>Osmosis IRL</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</guid><description>Osmosis Osmosis is term all of us come across during our schooling days.
In biology, osmosis is the movement of water molecules from a solution with a high concentration of water molecules to a solution with a lower concentration of water molecules, through a cell&amp;rsquo;s partially permeable membrane.
Water purification through reverse osmosis is one of the popular application in our day to day life.
Do we see anything similar to Osmosis in real life?</description></item><item><title>Project Update - 3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-3/</guid><description>This is continuation in the series about our side project. This post is a follow up to the pervious post on various tools used to build the process of building the application
The Environment Core language used in our project is Python. Python is used to fetch details from API calls, cleaning the API return value, and also writing it into DB. Even though the language is very popular and user ranges from amateurs to big corporations, it undergoes development.</description></item><item><title>Project Update - 2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</guid><description>This is a continuation to previous post on our new side project. Instead of building a spaghetti code that just works, we are approaching the entire process through the industry practise.
For example, the working components are modularised for easier maintenance. These individual modules are built on TDD approach, testing with every step of our development. The test results are passed through coverage to understand how much code is covered under our testing process.</description></item><item><title>Personal help/maid affordability - a social indicator?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</guid><description>One of the major difference between developed and developing nation is the way we treat the labours. Usually when a nation grows it concentrates on creating wealth. The wealth, once gets generated it tends to flock together and the rich gets super rich at the cost of vulnerable populous. Once this gap gets too large, the society becomes unstable.
The struggle between the haves and have-nots are the root cause of most of the civil unrest, gradually turning into civil war, if the gap is left unchecked.</description></item><item><title>Are you envious of younger generation?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</guid><description>Scene 1: During school days Teacher : Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you finish your homework?
Student : We experienced powercut all through the evening. And so, the home
T : Don&amp;rsquo;t say unnecessary reason in your age we were reading under the street lamp.
Scene 2: During college days College student : I need a bike to commute to college.
Parent : In your age we were walking n Kilometers to catch the government bus to college, your generation needs private vehicles at this young age?</description></item><item><title>Project Update - 1</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-1/</guid><description>Everyone of us think(or worry) about future, especially in 30s. Likewise, I worry about financial stability of my future. The retirement comes top of the list among the various worries. And so, I started investement. The investment includes various vahicles - Mutual fund, stocks and fixed components. Investing is a beast; tracking the investment is like taming the beast. For tracking the progress there are (literally) endless apps coming into to market.</description></item></channel></rss>