<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2023/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:36:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meetings are bad</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re part of a workforce, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand when I say meetings are bad. How to make it better or avoid it becoming worser? By removing the uncertainity from the equation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="case-1-a-message-from-your-spouse">Case 1: A message from your spouse&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekday. You&amp;rsquo;re in a middle of a task which should be completed in next few hours. Your phone beeps. There is a message from your spouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We need to talk. Come home soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fear + Confusion + Hope = Life?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear--confusion--hope-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear--confusion--hope-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a very, very small post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always wonder if uncertainty is bad, possibly the worst feature of life, or may be a bug in life. But uncertainty is not something new that we tend to experience recently. Since the earliest times, uncertainty has been part of life. Thinking out loud, waking up next morning is as uncertain as the weather.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="fear">Fear&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Earth has gone through several extinctions before taking its current form. According to the experts, it has gone through the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extinction_event">Big Five Mass Extinction&lt;/a>.
Apart from these extinction events, we understand now that many species go kaput every day. We could be the ones on any day, and the day hasn&amp;rsquo;t arrived yet. Recently, a microbe has shown us how brittle we are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Experience with raising PR</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post deals with my experience on contributing to the open source project - Microsoft Documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-first-pr">My first PR&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is not my first PR to an OSS. My very first contribution was to &lt;a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/pull/581">foambubble/foam&lt;/a>. The pull request adds licence file to the repo. Yea, I know. This may not qualifies for &lt;em>core&lt;/em> technical task. Nevertheless its my contribution. This lead to my Github badge - &lt;a href="https://github.com/dheepakg?tab=achievements&amp;amp;achievement=pull-shark">Pull Shark&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started interacting with the developers on the fix on April 14&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2021. Foam&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/riccardoferretti">riccardoferretti&lt;/a> was helpful. After series of conversation and some corrections, my changes were merged on April 19&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2021. Just 4 days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Data Visualization</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/why-data-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/why-data-visualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>Why I chose to pursue a journey in Data Visualization? This post is an explainer to the above question.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="what-do-i-do-for-living">What do I do for living?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Data Engineering is my day job. SQL and Python have fed me and kept me going for last decade. For the uninitiated, the work involves fetching data from several sources and loading into desired target. The &lt;em>source&lt;/em> and &lt;em>target&lt;/em> could be a database, API endpoint, or file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What do you pray for</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="consoling-a-crying-child">Consoling a crying child&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Last week, my kid fell ill. It was a viral fever with cold. Due to the intense cold, she was struggling to breathe and had ear pain. We were constantly clearing up the nasal passage and helping her with breathing. However, she was helpless with ear pain. As per the pediatrician&amp;rsquo;s instructions, we gave her a tonic to relieve her ear pain. The medicine is not a magic potion to heal instantaneously; it was slow process. Her body takes time to act on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The way a child learns</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of late I&amp;rsquo;m spending good amount of time with my toddler. The things she learns and the way she communicates is intriguing me. To be frank, I believe almost every kid does the same, more or less. But as I am seeing her development from very close I do observe on how she learns.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- 1. Imitatates what an elder does. repeating -->
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Imitation&lt;/strong>: She imitates us. Whatever we do she tries to replicate us. For example, she tries to saute the imaginary food on her toy kitchen set.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 2. Does learn from everyone, adult, elder sibling, animals, birds. No ego. -->
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No Ego&lt;/strong>: They doesn&amp;rsquo;t decide on whom to copy from. She mimics what her cousin does. The cousin we are talking about is barely an year old. She sees something new, she copis it; no discrimination on age.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 3. Questions without thinking what others will think -->
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not thinking what others thinking&lt;/strong>: She doesn&amp;rsquo;t consider what others thinking. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it this factor stops us from doing what we love. Having said that, sometimes she screams in public place irritating fellow beings.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 4. Pattern matching. Kinnam vs kannam -->
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Identifying patterns&lt;/strong>: Numbers are abstract concept for a toddler. Yet, on saying 3, she runs. Its more like a pattern matching than understanding 1-2-3.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 5. Observing all the time -->
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observing all the time&lt;/strong>: There is no dedicated learning time for her. She just goes on to observer and mimic all the time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fumbling 145 days long kindle reading streak</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</guid><description>&lt;p>If my memory serves right, Snapchat popularised the &lt;em>streak&lt;/em> phenomena. Later on, the amount popularity and stickiness it creates among the user, many companies jumped on the band wagon - fitness trackers, calories trackers and many more. What the streak does is it creates a habit among the users and make them to use the particular service on daily basis. Also, it creates a sense of pride with the longer streak on has.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3 - v3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a follow up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href="../post-062-visual-site-map-1/">same name&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-new">What&amp;rsquo;s new?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tooltip - Earlier, we were employing the browser&amp;rsquo;s native tooltip. With this update we have customised tooltip with publish date and categories along with the title of post.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transitions - On hovering the circles turns green and tooltip pops up.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
 &lt;style>
 .tooltip {
 position: absolute;
 font-family: monospace;
 pointer-events: none;
 background: silver;
 color: black;
 /* width: 400px; */
 text-align: left;
 border-radius: 6px;
 padding: 5px 5px;
 left: 50%;
 margin-left: -60px;
 z-index: 1;
 }

 .tooltip::after {
 content: "";
 position: relative;
 top: 100%;
 /* left: 0; */
 margin-left: -5px;
 border-width: 8px;
 border-style: solid;
 border-color: transparent transparent transparent transparent;
 }
 &lt;/style>
 &lt;body>
 &lt;div class="canvas">&lt;/div>
 &lt;script src="https://d3js.org/d3.v7.min.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;script src="http://labratrevenge.com/d3-tip/javascripts/d3.tip.v0.6.3.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;script src="index.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;/body>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Scope for improvement&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3 - v2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/05/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/05/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3-v2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a follow up to last month&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href="../visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/">same name&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are few changes made to the chart.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Today marker: Instead of drawing a full line for the current year, we are allowing the line to grow with passing day. This is a major change.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transition: The trasnition effects are the major change here. Ironically, the amount of code change is minimum - tbh addition of 2 lines is all that&amp;rsquo;s needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hyperlinks: All the hyperlinks are made colored with dark blue, as this is the &lt;a href="https://www.w3schools.com/html/html_links_colors.asp#:~:text=By%20default%2C%20a%20link%20will,link%20is%20underlined%20and%20red">default color&lt;/a> in all browsers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tooltip: We have used &lt;code>title&lt;/code> tag to implement the tooltip. This is not a major change or in other words the tooltip can be better. For that we have to go for CSS method, which is still a bit far from my reach.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;body>
 &lt;div class="canvas">&lt;/div>
 &lt;script src="https://d3js.org/d3.v7.min.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;script src="index.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;/body>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Scope for improvement&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years - D3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years-d3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an attempt to recreate the earlier created &lt;a href="https://dheepakg.github.io/content/post/post-060-2023-04-08-posts-by-years.md">blog post&lt;/a> through D3js.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m more of backend developer, working predominantly in Python + SQL. But, trying out JS is long time wish, which got fufilled through a Udemy course and some good imspiration.&lt;/p>
&lt;body>
 &lt;div class="canvas">&lt;/div>
 &lt;script src="https://d3js.org/d3.v7.min.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;script src="index.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;/body>
&lt;p>The visuals can be improved vastly and can add few more options. But this post is to show the progress.
Also, this is an attempt to conform that D3JS output can be hosted on our static site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once in a while we stumble into something interesting while we are not looking for it. This is a post on how I came across a chart while going through an online course, the experience in replicating the chart, the lessons I learnt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The instructor of the course - &lt;a href="https://observablehq.com/@observablehq/datavizcourse">Course: Data Visualization Fundamentals and Best Practices&lt;/a> by ObservableHQ. While going through his website I found this interesting chart - &lt;a href="https://eagereyes.org/blog-calendar">Blog Calendar&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- What is the inspiration -->
&lt;h3 id="the-discovery">The discovery&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Displaying his blog posts over the years in a chart was something I&amp;rsquo;m seeing for the first time. Since then even during his class I was seeing it how it was built and imagining how it would look for my blog. During the time provide for the final assignment, I doubled down and spent time on exploring tools to recreate the chart.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple roles of a man</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</guid><description>&lt;!-- 1. Japanese proverb - 3 person; 1 he knows, another close one knows and another public knows -->
&lt;p>The 30s are tricky period. Till 20s you can survive with a student or young earner tag. In the late 20s, you experience what the freedom is. And, when you start feeling you can do whatever you can and reach wherever you want to in life. Now you&amp;rsquo;re in your 30s and most likely you got punched at your face.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>API, Configurations &amp; Database operation</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/api-configurations-database-operation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/api-configurations-database-operation/</guid><description>&lt;!-- The api used in our project -->
&lt;p>Right now the project focuses on creating dashboard for Mutual funds, and gradually adding other investement vehicles viz stocks, PPF, and EPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fetching-navs">Fetching NAVs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To track the mutual funds, we come across an API by &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuvarajl/">Yuvaraj Loganathan&lt;/a> - &lt;a href="https://www.mfapi.in/">MFAPI&lt;/a>. Thank you, Yuvaraj. The API gets updated on daily basis and free to access (as in free beer). For our project, which is not intended for any financial gain, this api is the right fit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osmosis IRL</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="osmosis">Osmosis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osmosis is term all of us come across during our schooling days.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In biology, osmosis is the movement of water molecules from a solution with a &lt;strong>high concentration of water molecules to a solution with a lower concentration&lt;/strong> of water molecules, through a cell&amp;rsquo;s partially permeable membrane.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Water purification through reverse osmosis is one of the popular application in our day to day life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do we see anything similar to Osmosis in real life?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Update - 3</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is continuation in the series about our side project. This post is a follow up to the pervious &lt;a href="post-055-2023-01-22-pf-dashboard-2.md">post on various tools&lt;/a> used to build the process of building the application&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- Python version -->
&lt;h3 id="the-environment">The Environment&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Core language used in our project is Python. Python is used to fetch details from API calls, cleaning the API return value, and also writing it into DB. Even though the language is very popular and user ranges from amateurs to big corporations, it undergoes development. Implying the new versions are created and released often. And so, setting up the environment is necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Update - 2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a continuation to previous post on our new &lt;a href="post-054-2023-01-01-pf-dashboard-1.md">side project&lt;/a>. Instead of building a spaghetti code that just works, we are approaching the entire process through the industry practise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the working components are modularised for easier maintenance. These individual modules are built on TDD approach, testing with every step of our development. The test results are passed through coverage to understand how much code is covered under our testing process. And, based on this coverage status the code is committed into Git repo. This regulates clean and working code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal help/maid affordability - a social indicator?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</guid><description>&lt;!-- Spreading rumour/stealing are not a big issue. -->
&lt;p>One of the major difference between developed and developing nation is the way we treat the labours. Usually when a nation grows it concentrates on creating wealth. The wealth, once gets generated it tends to flock together and the rich gets super rich at the cost of vulnerable populous. Once this gap gets too large, the society becomes unstable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://dheepakg.github.io/img/post-53-drawio.svg" alt="Flow of Wealth">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are you envious of younger generation?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="scene-1-during-school-days">Scene 1: During school days&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Teacher&lt;/em> : Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you finish your homework?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Student&lt;/em> : We experienced powercut all through the evening. And so, the home&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>T&lt;/em> : Don&amp;rsquo;t say unnecessary reason &lt;strong>in your age we were reading under the street lamp.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="scene-2-during-college-days">Scene 2: During college days&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;em>College student&lt;/em> : I need a bike to commute to college.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Parent&lt;/em> : In your age we were walking &lt;em>n&lt;/em> Kilometers to catch the government bus to college, your generation &lt;strong>needs private vehicles at this young age&lt;/strong>?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Update - 1</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-1/</guid><description>&lt;!-- Problem statement - Why? Artos is limited. Lets build it ourself. Mention various apps you tried;
complaining is easy, lets try to build and experience the pain-->
&lt;p>Everyone of us think(or worry) about future, especially in 30s. Likewise, I worry about financial stability of my future. The retirement comes top of the list among the various worries. And so, I started investement. The investment includes various vahicles - Mutual fund, stocks and fixed components. Investing is a beast; tracking the investment is like taming the beast. For tracking the progress there are (literally) endless apps coming into to market. You must either trade in your data or pay for some freemium features.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>