<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:51:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experience with raising PR</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post deals with my experience on contributing to the open source project - Microsoft Documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-first-pr">My first PR&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is not my first PR to an OSS. My very first contribution was to &lt;a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/pull/581">foambubble/foam&lt;/a>. The pull request adds licence file to the repo. Yea, I know. This may not qualifies for &lt;em>core&lt;/em> technical task. Nevertheless its my contribution. This lead to my Github badge - &lt;a href="https://github.com/dheepakg?tab=achievements&amp;amp;achievement=pull-shark">Pull Shark&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started interacting with the developers on the fix on April 14&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2021. Foam&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/riccardoferretti">riccardoferretti&lt;/a> was helpful. After series of conversation and some corrections, my changes were merged on April 19&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2021. Just 4 days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Update - 2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/project-update-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a continuation to previous post on our new &lt;a href="post-054-2023-01-01-pf-dashboard-1.md">side project&lt;/a>. Instead of building a spaghetti code that just works, we are approaching the entire process through the industry practise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the working components are modularised for easier maintenance. These individual modules are built on TDD approach, testing with every step of our development. The test results are passed through coverage to understand how much code is covered under our testing process. And, based on this coverage status the code is committed into Git repo. This regulates clean and working code.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>