<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dataViz on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/dataviz/</link><description>Recent content in dataViz on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/dataviz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visualization: Post grouped by years</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/04/visualization-post-grouped-by-years/</guid><description>Once in a while we stumble into something interesting while we are not looking for it. This is a post on how I came across a chart while going through an online course, the experience in replicating the chart, the lessons I learnt.
The instructor of the course - Course: Data Visualization Fundamentals and Best Practices by ObservableHQ. While going through his website I found this interesting chart - Blog Calendar.</description></item><item><title>How much Income Tax Are We Paying?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/how-much-income-tax-are-we-paying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 08:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/how-much-income-tax-are-we-paying/</guid><description>During the last months of every financial year, there is a tradition, a custom to keep ourselves sane - ranting on tax that we suffered through the year, and any returns we can expect from the taxmen.
In one of the ranting sessions, we had an interesting conversation.
How much tax are we paying?.
What is so interesting?
The tax must be either 25% (new regime) or 30% (old regime).</description></item><item><title>A backend dev's journey into JS world - Part I</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 13:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</guid><description>I use SQL and Python to earn my bread. Being an ETL developer turned Data Engineer, my work is to fetch data from different sources, cleaning it, and making it consumption ready before storing it in some storage space - database, S3 et al.
It&amp;rsquo;s amusing to know that someone will be consuming this data and pull insights from it like a magician pulling a rabbit off his hat. The reporting tools were the go-to place to churn these processed data.</description></item></channel></rss>