<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Imported on Dheepak's blog</title><link>/tags/imported/</link><description>Recent content in Imported on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 20:47:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/imported/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Final frontier for AI could be decoding Sarcasm</title><link>/post/2018-06-03-final-frontier-ai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 20:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2018-06-03-final-frontier-ai/</guid><description>Sarcasm, according to Google is “ the use of irony to mock or convey contempt”. Interpreting it could be final frontier for AI.
Understanding Sarcastic line is a complex process. Depends on lots of variables — context, body language, tone modulation and so on. To be fair there is not proper/scientific way to decode sarcasm. To add to it, degree of closeness is (kinda) proportional to complexity of sarcasm.
In one of the scene Deadpool 2 movie, the lead actor was questioned who he is.</description></item><item><title>What is farming — Biz or Charity?</title><link>/post/2020-04-01-what-is-farming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 21:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-04-01-what-is-farming/</guid><description>Occupation (for-profit) or welfare/charity (non-profit)?
This is the question which started a long conversation with my friend over Whatsapp.
Why does it matter? Everything depends on the answer. If it’s Occupation, you can tax them for the revenue, likewise you can insure them so they can land safe in times of tragedy. Or if its a welfare, government can take it or some NGOs can chip in with funding from benevolent sponsors.</description></item><item><title>Democracy, a silver bullet?</title><link>/post/2017-05-06-democracy-silver-bullet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2017-05-06-democracy-silver-bullet/</guid><description>I’m a big fan of Democratic government. Went to war, in cyber world, with my friends whenever they say Saudi Arabia/China style of government is better than D-government. I’m pro-democracy because I believe in free will of humans.
So far, every dictator has ruled the people, crushed the basic rights in the name of religion, communism, socialism et al. We are not animals to be herded by some dictator. On the other end of spectrum, we have democracy.</description></item></channel></rss>