<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>India on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/india/</link><description>Recent content in India on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:29:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EVMs should be avoided for Indian elections - Why?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/evms-should-be-avoided-for-indian-elections-why/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/evms-should-be-avoided-for-indian-elections-why/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a country, 1990&amp;rsquo;s are changing times for India. The nation saw some of the interesting transformations, which would be an unimaginable tale even a decade earlier for Geo-political experts. The changes ranges from Economic stance of the country to opening up to private cable channels to introduction of Internet to the masses (the snail-paced dial-ups).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The election commission too hopped into the transformation train. From the conventional paper based ballot, the Electronic Voting Machines were introduced. As like any other new stuff, this was unwelcomed by many, especially every losing party started blaming on the foul play surrounding the EVM. To mitigate the foul play, as a 2nd level defense, the EC introduced &lt;a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/elections/lok-sabha/india/what-is-vvpat/articleshow/68667136.cms">VVPAT system&lt;/a>. Here, a paper trail is maintained alongside the digital recording of voting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is farming — Biz or Charity?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/02/what-is-farming-biz-or-charity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 21:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/02/what-is-farming-biz-or-charity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Occupation (for-profit) or welfare/charity (non-profit)?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the question which started a long conversation with my friend over Whatsapp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why does it matter? Everything depends on the answer. If it’s Occupation, you can tax them for the revenue, likewise you can insure them so they can land safe in times of tragedy. Or if its a welfare, government can take it or some NGOs can chip in with funding from benevolent sponsors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Democracy, a silver bullet?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2017/05/democracy-a-silver-bullet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2017/05/democracy-a-silver-bullet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a big fan of Democratic government. Went to war, in cyber world, with my friends whenever they say Saudi Arabia/China style of government is better than D-government. I’m pro-democracy because I believe in free will of humans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far, every dictator has ruled the people, crushed the basic rights in the name of religion, communism, socialism et al. We are not animals to be herded by some dictator. On the other end of spectrum, we have democracy. Governments &amp;amp; leaders selected by the people, for the people. Theoretically, we will be having a better leader under Democracy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>