<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 22:21:33 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A backend dev's journey into JS world - Part I</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 13:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/08/a-backend-devs-journey-into-js-world-part-i/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use SQL and Python to earn my bread. Being an ETL developer turned Data Engineer, my work is to fetch data from different sources, cleaning it, and making it consumption ready before storing it in some storage space - database, S3 et al.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s amusing to know that someone will be consuming this data and pull insights from it like a magician pulling a rabbit off his hat. The reporting tools were the go-to place to churn these processed data. The decision-makers use the reports generated by these tools. The reports are mostly limited to tables, bar, line, or pie charts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyConIndia 2019</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>My primary source of Python and Python related news was/is &lt;a href="https://talkpython.fm">Python podcast&lt;/a>, since 2016. In 2018, I came to know about Pycon taking place in Cleveland, OH. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zDVlqeOT2XY&amp;amp;list=PLP8GkvaIxJP281FqVlJBgHGyMRvP9NtYN">Dan Bader&amp;rsquo;s vlog on PyCon &amp;lsquo;18&lt;/a> was another pull factor towards the PyCon. Due to the ticket pricing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to it. In H2 of 2018, I returned to India, and was looking forward to attend PyConIndia, which should be affordable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyConIndia &amp;lsquo;19 is taking place in Chennai, which happened to be my second home. There can&amp;rsquo;t be anymore reason to miss the conference. The ticket booking opened for PyConIndia on one fine day. Then I did booked a ticket, sadly couldn&amp;rsquo;t book the early bird ticket.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>