<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2024/</link><description>Recent content in 2024 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflection on daily journaling</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</guid><description>The last quarter of 2023 was spent away from family for work related in a nordic country. The country is small. The Population density is much smaller. From the land of crowded spaces, this was taking a toll. Staying away from friends and family adds to this as well.
Just to fight off the boredom and depression, I resumed filling the journal on daily basis. Following are the reflections of the process.</description></item><item><title>Index Movement - Visualization</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</guid><description>Why? To keep myself from overthinking or having negative thoughts, I should focus my energy on something creative. Also, the creativity should pique my curiosity. Essentially, I should spend time learning something. Personal finance is something that we monitor and learn about in a daily manner. The PF has a variety of numbers and data to deal with. It&amp;rsquo;s more like clay that allows you to come up with any sculpture.</description></item><item><title>How was 2023?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s very common to look back what happened after an event. This post is about looking back at the past year through various criteria,
Personal life Career Hobby Finance Personal Life Work-life balance oculd have been better, its not like the employer is squeezing me. But its my ability to give priority to the family. If at all one thing I need to work on this year, that would be more time spent with family and cultivating memories.</description></item></channel></rss>