<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2024/</link><description>Recent content in 2024 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Event Update: M2W Conclave 2.0</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</guid><description>div.rightBox { position: absolute; right: 0; width: 230px; height: 250px; border: 3px solid grey; } Intro This is about an event or a gathering around the theme of personal finance. The crowd gathered is through the Youtube channel - Muthaleetukalam (முதலீட்டுக்களம்) translates to &amp;lsquo;Investment sector&amp;rsquo;, thanks Google. This is coordinated by iThought Wealth&amp;rsquo;s Shyam Shekhar through his milestones2wealth, a portal to make Making Small Investors THINK BIG!.
My PoV I started following the channel during the lockdown, just like million other self-proclaimed investors.</description></item><item><title>My Prayer</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</guid><description>To start with I&amp;rsquo;m not a religious person. Meaning I don&amp;rsquo;t strictly follow the religious activities, I do constantly question the practises. I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether I&amp;rsquo;m an atheist or an agnostic. But I do believe there could be some powerful entity. Could be a god, family of gods or nature.
When I was living abroad for the work purpose, I need a social interaction. That made me to visit temple every week, almost.</description></item><item><title>Analog Clock</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/07/analog-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/07/analog-clock/</guid><description>First we started with a circle. The dial is composed of a bigger circle and a smaller one - a center point.
With the dial is in place, next step is to add arms of the clock. The end result should have 3 arms - depicting hours, minutes and seconds. To have quicker feedback we started with seconds arm.
Drawing the radius solves the initial position of seconds arm.</description></item><item><title>Investing in real estates</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</guid><description>This is a write up on my thoughts abour real estate as investment. The real estate implies plot as well as the home.
To describe my disinterest towards RE, first we should see how the system works with respect to RE. To make it clear I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about REITs.
This is entirely unregulated space. Meaning, there is no check and balance to help the consumers. With no regulations, the black money is very very common.</description></item><item><title>Learnings from working with external teams</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</guid><description>With the recent change in the role from data engineer to lead data engineer, I&amp;rsquo;m regularly interacting with different teams, both upstream and downstream. It had become routine to have meetings with the counterparties to understand their difficulties. After all, we are a tree but a part of a forest. Diversity factor It might annoy us to hear about diversity from the MNCs again and again. However, for the proper functioning of the organization, it is essential to have associates from various backgrounds.</description></item><item><title>Reflections on recent changes in work place</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</guid><description>The last few weeks have been tough. The problem seems to originate from all three avenues: life, work, and the social circle. My child is demanding that I play with her more regularly and for more time. By size, my social circle is small. I feel the size further shrinks due to my inability to speak or interact with my close friends. Even though the friends usually accept the fact that life is getting busier, the crack appears nonetheless.</description></item><item><title>Tax and Death</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</guid><description>.. in this world nothing can be said to be certain, except death and taxes
&amp;amp;mdash Benjamin Franklin[1]
Tax I came across a meme - Tax is a subscription fee to the state we live in. In a way the statement is true.
You owe some money to the land where you live. Most of the countries collect it income tax, some countries do survive without collecting income tax[2].</description></item><item><title>Reflection on daily journaling</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</guid><description>The last quarter of 2023 was spent away from family for work related in a nordic country. The country is small. The Population density is much smaller. From the land of crowded spaces, this was taking a toll. Staying away from friends and family adds to this as well.
Just to fight off the boredom and depression, I resumed filling the journal on daily basis. Following are the reflections of the process.</description></item><item><title>Index Movement - Visualization</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</guid><description>Why? To keep myself from overthinking or having negative thoughts, I should focus my energy on something creative. Also, the creativity should pique my curiosity. Essentially, I should spend time learning something. Personal finance is something that we monitor and learn about in a daily manner. The PF has a variety of numbers and data to deal with. It&amp;rsquo;s more like clay that allows you to come up with any sculpture.</description></item><item><title>How was 2023?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s very common to look back what happened after an event. This post is about looking back at the past year through various criteria,
Personal life Career Hobby Finance Personal Life Work-life balance oculd have been better, its not like the employer is squeezing me. But its my ability to give priority to the family. If at all one thing I need to work on this year, that would be more time spent with family and cultivating memories.</description></item></channel></rss>