<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024 on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2024/</link><description>Recent content in 2024 on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 22:28:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/year/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Over-confidence is the safety risk</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/12/over-confidence-is-the-safety-risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/12/over-confidence-is-the-safety-risk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Few years ago, I was working in a Chennai, 500 KM away from Coimbatore, where my family resides. The usual trip between the cities is on long weekends, so does the large crowd settled in &lt;em>Singara&lt;/em> Chennai. With a huge crowd looking to travel back on long weekends, reserving a seat was not easiest thing to do. I booked my ticket a week back and in relaxed manner went to boarding point. While checking the ticket I noticed the booking was for previous day. There was no way to travel back on that day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I'm planning to get started on Deep Learning?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/11/how-im-planning-to-get-started-on-deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/11/how-im-planning-to-get-started-on-deep-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is to describe how I find the book &lt;a href="https://rosmulski.gumroad.com/l/learn_machine_learning">Meta Learning: How To Learn Deep Learning And Thrive In The Digital World&lt;/a> is giving me a hope and road map to learn Deep Learning. Not only learning DL and also where to go from there viz Kaggle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="who-am-i">Who am I?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m part of Data landscape for more than a decade now. I started as ETL developer, then evolved into Data Engineer. When I was crawling the ETL world, the Data Scientists were already declared as the &lt;a href="https://hbr.org/2012/10/data-scientist-the-sexiest-job-of-the-21st-century">sexiest job&lt;/a>, and Big Data was a novelty. The 1st time I heard about the power of the data and analytics was from the famous &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/02/16/how-target-figured-out-a-teen-girl-was-pregnant-before-her-father-did/">Forbes article on Target&lt;/a>. I was awestruck. Then later on I started working on Big Data with AWS, as a Data Engineer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Event Update: M2W Conclave 2.0</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/09/event-update-m2w-conclave-2.0/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This is about an event or a gathering around the theme of personal finance. The crowd gathered is through the Youtube channel - Muthaleetukalam (முதலீட்டுக்களம்) translates to &lt;em>&amp;lsquo;Investment sector&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>, &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=ta&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;text=%E0%AE%AE%E0%AF%81%E0%AE%A4%E0%AE%B2%E0%AF%80%E0%AE%9F%E0%AF%8D%E0%AE%9F%E0%AF%81%E0%AE%95%E0%AF%8D%E0%AE%95%E0%AE%B3%E0%AE%AE%E0%AF%8D&amp;amp;op=translate">thanks Google&lt;/a>. This is coordinated by iThought Wealth&amp;rsquo;s Shyam Shekhar through his &lt;a href="https://milestones2wealth.com/">milestones2wealth&lt;/a>, a portal to make &lt;em>Making
Small Investors THINK BIG!&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;style>
div.rightBox {
 position: absolute;
 right: 0;
 width: 230px;
 height: 250px;
 border: 3px solid grey;
}

&lt;/style>
&lt;!-- The history -->
&lt;h1 id="my-pov">My PoV&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I started following the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@muthaleetukalam">channel&lt;/a> during the lockdown, just like million other self-proclaimed investors. The channel is not for trader/speculator/FnO players or gamblers. The videos pops up everyday since the lockdown times. The primary theme is investor behavior, or current events with respect of finance or economics. Some day special guests gets featured, to share their experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Event Update: Consecration</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/event-update-consecration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/event-update-consecration/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m in the midway between an atheist, agnostic and a religious person. My particiaption in events based out of religious tradition, is almost always doubtful. Yet, I was part of this community gathering, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to cover the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- What it is and when? -->
&lt;p>When a temple gets built, it deserves sequence of rituals that adds spiritual and religious power to the deity living in the temple. As it is a belief based system, logical questioing doesn&amp;rsquo;t end well. The event took place on August 17-19, 2024.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Prayer</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</guid><description>&lt;p>To start with I&amp;rsquo;m not a religious person. Meaning I don&amp;rsquo;t strictly follow the religious activities, I do constantly question the practises. I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether I&amp;rsquo;m an atheist or an agnostic. But I do believe there could be some powerful entity. Could be a god, family of gods or nature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was living abroad for the work purpose, I need a social interaction. That made me to visit temple every week, almost. I do consider myself a rational person, so the conventional prayers like asking the God to give this or that made no sense. After all it is an all knowing entity. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it knows what should be given to me?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analog Clock</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/07/analog-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/07/analog-clock/</guid><description>&lt;p>First we started with a circle. The dial is composed of a bigger circle and a smaller one - a center point.&lt;/p>
&lt;body>
 &lt;div class="one">&lt;/div>
 &lt;script src="https://d3js.org/d3.v7.min.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;script src="./1.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;/body>
&lt;p>With the dial is in place, next step is to add arms of the clock. The end result should have 3 arms - depicting hours, minutes and seconds. To have quicker feedback we started with seconds arm.&lt;/p>
&lt;body>
 &lt;div class="two">&lt;/div>
 &lt;script src="https://d3js.org/d3.v7.min.js">&lt;/script>
 &lt;script src="./2.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;/body>
&lt;p>Drawing the radius solves the initial position of seconds arm. However, to have the arm goes around the clock, we need to calculate &lt;code>(x,y)&lt;/code> coordinates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investing in real estates</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a write up on my thoughts abour real estate as investment. The real estate implies plot as well as the home.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- How it works - big in capital -->
&lt;p>To describe my disinterest towards RE, first we should see how the system works with respect to RE. To make it clear I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about REITs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is entirely unregulated space. Meaning, there is no check and balance to help the consumers. With no regulations, the black money is very very common. As the transaction is under the regulator&amp;rsquo;s radar, there is no place to approach for any type of grievances.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learnings from working with external teams</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the recent change in the role from data engineer to &lt;a href="https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/">lead data engineer&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m regularly interacting with different teams, both upstream and downstream. It had become routine to have meetings with the counterparties to understand their difficulties. After all, we are a tree but a part of a forest.  &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diversity-factor">Diversity factor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It might annoy us to hear about diversity from the MNCs again and again. However, for the proper functioning of the organization, it is essential to have associates from various backgrounds. This plurality ensures different ideas and approaches to a problem, which in turn gives the authorities the ability to compare and pick a better, more efficient solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflections on recent changes in work place</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last few weeks have been tough. The problem seems to originate from all three avenues: life, work, and the social circle. My child is demanding that I play with her more regularly and for more time. By size, my social circle is small. I feel the size further shrinks due to my inability to speak or interact with my close friends. Even though the friends usually accept the fact that life is getting busier, the crack appears nonetheless.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tax and Death</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>.. in this world nothing can be said to be certain, except death and taxes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;amp;mdash &lt;cite>Benjamin Franklin[1]&lt;/cite>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="tax">Tax&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I came across a meme - &lt;em>Tax is a subscription fee to the state we live in&lt;/em>. In a way the statement is true.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You owe some money to the land where you live. Most of the countries collect it income tax, some countries do survive without collecting income tax[2]. Having said that Income Tax is not the only tax the state can impose. It charge us via some other means too - corporate tax, Value added tax or Service/sales tax.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflection on daily journaling</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last quarter of 2023 was spent away from family for work related in a nordic country. The country is small. The Population density is much smaller. From the land of crowded spaces, this was taking a toll. Staying away from friends and family adds to this as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just to fight off the boredom and depression, I resumed filling the journal on daily basis. Following are the reflections of the process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Index Movement - Visualization</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/index-movement-visualization/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why">Why?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To keep myself from overthinking or having negative thoughts, I should focus my energy on something creative. Also, the creativity should pique my curiosity. Essentially, I should spend time learning something. Personal finance is something that we monitor and learn about in a daily manner. The PF has a variety of numbers and data to deal with. It&amp;rsquo;s more like clay that allows you to come up with any sculpture.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How was 2023?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very common to look back what happened after an event. This post is about looking back at the past year through various criteria,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Personal life&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Career&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hobby&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="personal-life">Personal Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Work-life balance oculd have been better, its not like the employer is squeezing me. But its my ability to give priority to the family. If at all one thing I need to work on this year, that would be more time spent with family and cultivating memories.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>