<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:04:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Prayer</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/08/my-prayer/</guid><description>&lt;p>To start with I&amp;rsquo;m not a religious person. Meaning I don&amp;rsquo;t strictly follow the religious activities, I do constantly question the practises. I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether I&amp;rsquo;m an atheist or an agnostic. But I do believe there could be some powerful entity. Could be a god, family of gods or nature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was living abroad for the work purpose, I need a social interaction. That made me to visit temple every week, almost. I do consider myself a rational person, so the conventional prayers like asking the God to give this or that made no sense. After all it is an all knowing entity. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it knows what should be given to me?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What do you pray for</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="consoling-a-crying-child">Consoling a crying child&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Last week, my kid fell ill. It was a viral fever with cold. Due to the intense cold, she was struggling to breathe and had ear pain. We were constantly clearing up the nasal passage and helping her with breathing. However, she was helpless with ear pain. As per the pediatrician&amp;rsquo;s instructions, we gave her a tonic to relieve her ear pain. The medicine is not a magic potion to heal instantaneously; it was slow process. Her body takes time to act on it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple roles of a man</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</guid><description>&lt;!-- 1. Japanese proverb - 3 person; 1 he knows, another close one knows and another public knows -->
&lt;p>The 30s are tricky period. Till 20s you can survive with a student or young earner tag. In the late 20s, you experience what the freedom is. And, when you start feeling you can do whatever you can and reach wherever you want to in life. Now you&amp;rsquo;re in your 30s and most likely you got punched at your face.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What if: Google suspends your account?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/08/what-if-google-suspends-your-account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 09:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/08/what-if-google-suspends-your-account/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re waking up to your alarm. On turning the alarm off you notice there is some error notification, but you casually swipe it away to get started on the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While you&amp;rsquo;re commuting to your office you notice the Whatsapp backup ran into some error, now you &lt;em>ignore&lt;/em> it as it&amp;rsquo;s not something important. During your tea-break in office you are opening Google Photos to look at your child&amp;rsquo;s memories. Just like earlier notifications Googl Photos too throw some error at you, now you can&amp;rsquo;t able to download the backed-up photos.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>