<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tax and Death</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</guid><description>.. in this world nothing can be said to be certain, except death and taxes
&amp;amp;mdash Benjamin Franklin[1]
Tax I came across a meme - Tax is a subscription fee to the state we live in. In a way the statement is true.
You owe some money to the land where you live. Most of the countries collect it income tax, some countries do survive without collecting income tax[2].</description></item><item><title>What do you pray for</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/09/what-do-you-pray-for/</guid><description>Consoling a crying child Last week, my kid fell ill. It was a viral fever with cold. Due to the intense cold, she was struggling to breathe and had ear pain. We were constantly clearing up the nasal passage and helping her with breathing. However, she was helpless with ear pain. As per the pediatrician&amp;rsquo;s instructions, we gave her a tonic to relieve her ear pain. The medicine is not a magic potion to heal instantaneously; it was slow process.</description></item><item><title>Multiple roles of a man</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</guid><description>The 30s are tricky period. Till 20s you can survive with a student or young earner tag. In the late 20s, you experience what the freedom is. And, when you start feeling you can do whatever you can and reach wherever you want to in life. Now you&amp;rsquo;re in your 30s and most likely you got punched at your face.
Why 30s are so tough A simple answer is roles that each person plays.</description></item></channel></rss>