<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opinion on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 23:12:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Over-confidence is the safety risk</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/12/over-confidence-is-the-safety-risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/12/over-confidence-is-the-safety-risk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Few years ago, I was working in a Chennai, 500 KM away from Coimbatore, where my family resides. The usual trip between the cities is on long weekends, so does the large crowd settled in &lt;em>Singara&lt;/em> Chennai. With a huge crowd looking to travel back on long weekends, reserving a seat was not easiest thing to do. I booked my ticket a week back and in relaxed manner went to boarding point. While checking the ticket I noticed the booking was for previous day. There was no way to travel back on that day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tax and Death</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/tax-and-death/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>.. in this world nothing can be said to be certain, except death and taxes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;amp;mdash &lt;cite>Benjamin Franklin[1]&lt;/cite>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="tax">Tax&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I came across a meme - &lt;em>Tax is a subscription fee to the state we live in&lt;/em>. In a way the statement is true.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You owe some money to the land where you live. Most of the countries collect it income tax, some countries do survive without collecting income tax[2]. Having said that Income Tax is not the only tax the state can impose. It charge us via some other means too - corporate tax, Value added tax or Service/sales tax.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Osmosis IRL</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/02/osmosis-irl/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="osmosis">Osmosis&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Osmosis is term all of us come across during our schooling days.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In biology, osmosis is the movement of water molecules from a solution with a &lt;strong>high concentration of water molecules to a solution with a lower concentration&lt;/strong> of water molecules, through a cell&amp;rsquo;s partially permeable membrane.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Water purification through reverse osmosis is one of the popular application in our day to day life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do we see anything similar to Osmosis in real life?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal help/maid affordability - a social indicator?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/personal-help/maid-affordability-a-social-indicator/</guid><description>&lt;!-- Spreading rumour/stealing are not a big issue. -->
&lt;p>One of the major difference between developed and developing nation is the way we treat the labours. Usually when a nation grows it concentrates on creating wealth. The wealth, once gets generated it tends to flock together and the rich gets super rich at the cost of vulnerable populous. Once this gap gets too large, the society becomes unstable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://dheepakg.github.io/img/post-53-drawio.svg" alt="Flow of Wealth">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are you envious of younger generation?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 11:37:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/01/are-you-envious-of-younger-generation/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="scene-1-during-school-days">Scene 1: During school days&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Teacher&lt;/em> : Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you finish your homework?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Student&lt;/em> : We experienced powercut all through the evening. And so, the home&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>T&lt;/em> : Don&amp;rsquo;t say unnecessary reason &lt;strong>in your age we were reading under the street lamp.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h5 id="scene-2-during-college-days">Scene 2: During college days&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>&lt;em>College student&lt;/em> : I need a bike to commute to college.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Parent&lt;/em> : In your age we were walking &lt;em>n&lt;/em> Kilometers to catch the government bus to college, your generation &lt;strong>needs private vehicles at this young age&lt;/strong>?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yet another tech CEO of Indian origin</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/11/yet-another-tech-ceo-of-indian-origin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 20:06:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/11/yet-another-tech-ceo-of-indian-origin/</guid><description>&lt;p>From co-founder to CEO, Jack Dorsey was carrying Twitter&amp;rsquo;s identity for sometime now. He is not without controversies. Twitter and Facebook came to prominence on somewhat same time. Yet, Facebook became a cash-rich poster boy among the social media, Twitter lagging behind Facebook, unclear how to monetize the Twitter as a product. As a CEO, he was blamed for being CEO on Square and not concentrating on Twitter.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">+ Fun fact: Argawal joins the growing ranks of powerful US tech executives of Indian descent. Google, Microsoft, Adobe, IBM, Palo Alto Networks, and now Twitter are all run by people who grew up in India.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If you're approaching 20's or in early 20's</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/08/if-youre-approaching-20s-or-in-early-20s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 11:47:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/08/if-youre-approaching-20s-or-in-early-20s/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this write up, the &lt;em>hostel&lt;/em> is used to indicate not only limited to the boarding school but also staying away from parents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong> You must live in a hostel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All through these years since your arrival, you&amp;rsquo;ve a safety net named &lt;em>parents&lt;/em>. They cleaned your shitty bums, they fed you with the food that are handpicked for your well-being, they were there when you tumbled down, they taught you how to walk, eat, pee et al.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One needn't be proud</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/07/one-neednt-be-proud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 23:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/07/one-neednt-be-proud/</guid><description>&lt;p>Social Media is a petri dish, culturing cultured and uncultured humans in real time. Based on your followers and taste you develop your own bubble, reinforce the bubble&amp;rsquo;s collective thought and at some point of time you&amp;rsquo;ll start believing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One way to not get lost in the rabbit hole is to think the collective thought (trending topic) is wrong and trying to justify it. Then I came across this &amp;lsquo;-pride&amp;rsquo; posts. We are blindly getting proud of nation, the mother tongue, the city we line; heck, the caste we born to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The return of Newsletters</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/the-return-of-newsletters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/the-return-of-newsletters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Emails became so much intertwined in our daily life. Whatever the internet service it be, eventually it comes to identifying you only through your email&lt;sup id="a1">&lt;a href="#f1">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.
The newsletters used to be my source of information. I gradually unsubscribed to newsletters and marked the providers as important in my everyday feed of Twitter &amp;amp; Facebook.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a couple of first order effects,&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>I inadvertently started following so many users related to the news feeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The email inbox, once used to be zero inbox turned out to be filled with spams and filths&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Beyond First Order&lt;sup id="a2">&lt;a href="#f2">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Essentially, they're non-essentials</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/essentially-theyre-non-essentials/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/essentially-theyre-non-essentials/</guid><description>&lt;p>The future generations must be viewing &lt;em>this&lt;/em> as a biggest psychological experiment, worst case scenario and the inhumane practice to save humanity and much more. &lt;em>This&lt;/em> is COVID-19 &lt;strong>lockdown&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lockdown was imposed on March 25&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2020. Being a social animal, we went through a lot. The ill effects of lockdown ranges from anxiety induced due to potential job loss - &lt;a href="https://www.thehindu.com/business/indias-unemployment-rate-rises-to-2711-amid-covid-19-crisis-cmie/article31511006.ece">historic unemployment rate&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://money.cnn.com/2018/05/22/news/economy/1980s-millennials-great-recession-study/index.html">potential downturn of investments&lt;/a> in coming years, struggling to keep up with daily work-from-home with &lt;a href="https://theprint.in/opinion/pov/not-a-win-win-situation-why-we-should-not-work-from-home-after-the-covid-19-lockdown/397284/">it&amp;rsquo;s own challenges&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A curious question on reading?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/a-curious-question-on-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 11:07:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/06/a-curious-question-on-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>My &lt;em>SO&lt;/em> asked a curious question. I froze, like a Windows XP machine, couldn&amp;rsquo;t answer then. After the incident, for several nights, the question ran through in my head to decipher the answer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with little &lt;em>about me&lt;/em> . I like to read books. As of today, reading is one of the hobby for me. For her, reading is a boring chore, like majority around me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question was simple and on to the point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID-19: Political change on the cards?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/covid-19-political-change-on-the-cards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:10:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/covid-19-political-change-on-the-cards/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;em>outbreak&lt;/em> is here. Turned into &lt;a href="http://www.euro.who.int/en/health-topics/health-emergencies/coronavirus-covid-19/news/news/2020/3/who-announces-covid-19-outbreak-a-pandemic">Pandemic&lt;/a>, spreading across geographies without much of obstacles. The impact is felt in so many domains, from hospitals to hospitality, from tourism industry to ride-sharing. Governments are scrambling to slow down its spread. The corporates are equipping employees with work-from-home options. Unorganized sector is going for a toss. So, how could the COVID-19 affect the governing bodies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Late 2010s and the raise of Nationalists&lt;/strong>
The Nationalists or Conservatives or Right wingers are in raise in the 2&lt;sup>nd&lt;/sup> half of 2010s, across the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Couple of things that went unnoticed</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/couple-of-things-that-went-unnoticed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:01:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/couple-of-things-that-went-unnoticed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last July marks the Quadrennial year working in an MNC. These years had taught me several valuable lessons. Learnt either from first-hand experience or learning from others action. What I learnt is that our fundamentals are flawed as several important things are not taught at young age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are 2 important things that must be included in curriculum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.google.co.in/search?q=define%20career&amp;amp;cad=h">Career&lt;/a> vs. &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.in/search?q=define+job&amp;amp;cad=h">Job&lt;/a> : In earlier generation, its pride to be working with an employer for long duration (say, in terms years or decades). I have part of several farewells where in people will be treated well for part of the establishment and retiring is like a big event. That was the day in past. I don’t come across those celebration in recent times. One of my team mate, recently joined states that this is his 5th employer in 8 years. In this 8-year-long career he has been working with several domain and several tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shouldn’t there be some regulation – road side shops</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/shouldnt-there-be-some-regulation-road-side-shops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/shouldnt-there-be-some-regulation-road-side-shops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Waking up at the morning, after finishing morning-activities I noticed there was no water. I should have checked the water can in the night. Duh!! Should have called the water can vendor if I reached home came earlier. He did delivered the cans after a call and waiting for a hour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Breakfast time. Rushed out to road-side eatery. While waiting for dishes to be prepared, had conversation with the owner-cum-server, came to know that the continuous rain for 3 days the last week has affected their business. And, things went worse as they couldn’t repay the debt on that week. Still waiting for the dishes to get prepared, hunger made it the longest 10 minutes. Finally, it got ready. Then came another obstacle – traffic cop. He was questioning the owner, on whose permission they are running the stall on the road-side.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Guinea Pig Generation</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/12/the-guinea-pig-generation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 21:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/12/the-guinea-pig-generation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The generation born between 1985-95 has more or less seen the technology evolution from the fron seat. The advent of internet, landline giving up its place to mobile phones, more desk jobs than the labour intensive work. Through this journey, the lifestyle got altered to a large extent. Some of the changes are just an improvemnt to our life, while some or controversial in nature. I call them controversial as harmful effects are neither proved nor denied by scientific community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fight against Climate Change is not getting traction - Why?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/fight-against-climate-change-is-not-getting-traction-why/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 11:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/fight-against-climate-change-is-not-getting-traction-why/</guid><description>&lt;p>We all know the Climate change is real and happening now. This is a threat to the &lt;em>Human species&lt;/em>. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s a threat to the species not the entire planet. Why not we as a species cannot survive this? The nature will adapt to the changes. But, the new earth will no way close to the one we have now. Also, we got deviated from the natural evolution. Our life became sophisticated, without the necessary infrastructure we will kill ourself in the name of depression. So, we have to fight the Climatic changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EVMs should be avoided for Indian elections - Why?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/evms-should-be-avoided-for-indian-elections-why/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/evms-should-be-avoided-for-indian-elections-why/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a country, 1990&amp;rsquo;s are changing times for India. The nation saw some of the interesting transformations, which would be an unimaginable tale even a decade earlier for Geo-political experts. The changes ranges from Economic stance of the country to opening up to private cable channels to introduction of Internet to the masses (the snail-paced dial-ups).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The election commission too hopped into the transformation train. From the conventional paper based ballot, the Electronic Voting Machines were introduced. As like any other new stuff, this was unwelcomed by many, especially every losing party started blaming on the foul play surrounding the EVM. To mitigate the foul play, as a 2nd level defense, the EC introduced &lt;a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/elections/lok-sabha/india/what-is-vvpat/articleshow/68667136.cms">VVPAT system&lt;/a>. Here, a paper trail is maintained alongside the digital recording of voting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Final frontier for AI could be decoding Sarcasm</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/06/final-frontier-for-ai-could-be-decoding-sarcasm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 20:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/06/final-frontier-for-ai-could-be-decoding-sarcasm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sarcasm, according to Google is “ the use of irony to mock or convey contempt”. Interpreting it could be final frontier for AI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Understanding Sarcastic line is a complex process. Depends on lots of variables — context, body language, tone modulation and so on. To be fair there is not proper/scientific way to decode sarcasm. To add to it, degree of closeness is (kinda) proportional to complexity of sarcasm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the scene Deadpool 2 movie, the lead actor was questioned who he is. Responding, he says, “I’m Batman”. The whole theater erupts in laughter. You can understand this if you’re aware of Batman and his punchlines.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is farming — Biz or Charity?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/02/what-is-farming-biz-or-charity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 21:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2018/02/what-is-farming-biz-or-charity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Occupation (for-profit) or welfare/charity (non-profit)?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the question which started a long conversation with my friend over Whatsapp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why does it matter? Everything depends on the answer. If it’s Occupation, you can tax them for the revenue, likewise you can insure them so they can land safe in times of tragedy. Or if its a welfare, government can take it or some NGOs can chip in with funding from benevolent sponsors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Democracy, a silver bullet?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2017/05/democracy-a-silver-bullet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 22:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2017/05/democracy-a-silver-bullet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a big fan of Democratic government. Went to war, in cyber world, with my friends whenever they say Saudi Arabia/China style of government is better than D-government. I’m pro-democracy because I believe in free will of humans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far, every dictator has ruled the people, crushed the basic rights in the name of religion, communism, socialism et al. We are not animals to be herded by some dictator. On the other end of spectrum, we have democracy. Governments &amp;amp; leaders selected by the people, for the people. Theoretically, we will be having a better leader under Democracy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>