<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Observation on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/observation/</link><description>Recent content in Observation on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:24:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/observation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The way a child learns</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of late I&amp;rsquo;m spending good amount of time with my toddler. The things she learns and the way she communicates is intriguing me. To be frank, I believe almost every kid does the same, more or less. But as I am seeing her development from very close I do observe on how she learns.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- 1. Imitatates what an elder does. repeating -->
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Imitation&lt;/strong>: She imitates us. Whatever we do she tries to replicate us. For example, she tries to saute the imaginary food on her toy kitchen set.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 2. Does learn from everyone, adult, elder sibling, animals, birds. No ego. -->
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No Ego&lt;/strong>: They doesn&amp;rsquo;t decide on whom to copy from. She mimics what her cousin does. The cousin we are talking about is barely an year old. She sees something new, she copis it; no discrimination on age.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 3. Questions without thinking what others will think -->
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not thinking what others thinking&lt;/strong>: She doesn&amp;rsquo;t consider what others thinking. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it this factor stops us from doing what we love. Having said that, sometimes she screams in public place irritating fellow beings.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 4. Pattern matching. Kinnam vs kannam -->
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Identifying patterns&lt;/strong>: Numbers are abstract concept for a toddler. Yet, on saying 3, she runs. Its more like a pattern matching than understanding 1-2-3.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 5. Observing all the time -->
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observing all the time&lt;/strong>: There is no dedicated learning time for her. She just goes on to observer and mimic all the time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cross compatibility is key</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</guid><description>&lt;p>When my kid was on a mattress, she was hesitant to move around. Later on, with the comfort of the soft surface, she was rolling around without caring about her head getting hurt or gravity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything got changed when we let her crawl on the hard surface in the living room. She was getting hurt quite frequently - sometimes stepping on a toy, or hard landing on her head while rolling on the floor, or simply butting on something at her head level. Slowly, she got learned to avoid those hurting her. These days she evaluates the surfaces before taking another step.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>