<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Observation on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/observation/</link><description>Recent content in Observation on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:35:57 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/observation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Recurring Theme in my life</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/05/a-recurring-theme-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/05/a-recurring-theme-in-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>What I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss here is a theme that&amp;rsquo;s recurring all through my life. I ran into some trouble and I lose my sleep for few days, but at an unexpected situation I talk about it to someone and voila there comes a solution. Much worse, the concerned people who I thought I&amp;rsquo;m harming doesn&amp;rsquo;t even take it as a big deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overthinking-leads-to-no-where">Overthinking leads to no where&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I start simulating the impact of some of my actions, I delve into the extremes, a negative extreme. This at times saves me from potentially embarrassing situations. However, many times I indulge in self harm through overthinking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investing in real estates</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a write up on my thoughts abour real estate as investment. The real estate implies plot as well as the home.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- How it works - big in capital -->
&lt;p>To describe my disinterest towards RE, first we should see how the system works with respect to RE. To make it clear I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about REITs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is entirely unregulated space. Meaning, there is no check and balance to help the consumers. With no regulations, the black money is very very common. As the transaction is under the regulator&amp;rsquo;s radar, there is no place to approach for any type of grievances.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meetings are bad</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re part of a workforce, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand when I say meetings are bad. How to make it better or avoid it becoming worser? By removing the uncertainity from the equation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="case-1-a-message-from-your-spouse">Case 1: A message from your spouse&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekday. You&amp;rsquo;re in a middle of a task which should be completed in next few hours. Your phone beeps. There is a message from your spouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We need to talk. Come home soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The way a child learns</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/07/the-way-a-child-learns/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of late I&amp;rsquo;m spending good amount of time with my toddler. The things she learns and the way she communicates is intriguing me. To be frank, I believe almost every kid does the same, more or less. But as I am seeing her development from very close I do observe on how she learns.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- 1. Imitatates what an elder does. repeating -->
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Imitation&lt;/strong>: She imitates us. Whatever we do she tries to replicate us. For example, she tries to saute the imaginary food on her toy kitchen set.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 2. Does learn from everyone, adult, elder sibling, animals, birds. No ego. -->
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No Ego&lt;/strong>: They doesn&amp;rsquo;t decide on whom to copy from. She mimics what her cousin does. The cousin we are talking about is barely an year old. She sees something new, she copis it; no discrimination on age.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 3. Questions without thinking what others will think -->
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not thinking what others thinking&lt;/strong>: She doesn&amp;rsquo;t consider what others thinking. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it this factor stops us from doing what we love. Having said that, sometimes she screams in public place irritating fellow beings.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 4. Pattern matching. Kinnam vs kannam -->
&lt;ol start="4">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Identifying patterns&lt;/strong>: Numbers are abstract concept for a toddler. Yet, on saying 3, she runs. Its more like a pattern matching than understanding 1-2-3.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;!-- 5. Observing all the time -->
&lt;ol start="5">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Observing all the time&lt;/strong>: There is no dedicated learning time for her. She just goes on to observer and mimic all the time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple roles of a man</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/03/multiple-roles-of-a-man/</guid><description>&lt;!-- 1. Japanese proverb - 3 person; 1 he knows, another close one knows and another public knows -->
&lt;p>The 30s are tricky period. Till 20s you can survive with a student or young earner tag. In the late 20s, you experience what the freedom is. And, when you start feeling you can do whatever you can and reach wherever you want to in life. Now you&amp;rsquo;re in your 30s and most likely you got punched at your face.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cross compatibility is key</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</guid><description>&lt;p>When my kid was on a mattress, she was hesitant to move around. Later on, with the comfort of the soft surface, she was rolling around without caring about her head getting hurt or gravity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything got changed when we let her crawl on the hard surface in the living room. She was getting hurt quite frequently - sometimes stepping on a toy, or hard landing on her head while rolling on the floor, or simply butting on something at her head level. Slowly, she got learned to avoid those hurting her. These days she evaluates the surfaces before taking another step.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What makes Rust interesting?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/what-makes-rust-interesting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/08/what-makes-rust-interesting/</guid><description>&lt;p>Podcasts. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got introduced to the Rust language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the PythonBytes &lt;a href="https://pythonbytes.fm/episodes/show/138/will-pyoxidizer-weld-shut-one-of-python-s-major-gaps">episode&lt;/a> I heard about the PyOxidizer for the first time. Basically, it uses Rust to bundle Python code into an &lt;a href="https://gregoryszorc.com/blog/2019/06/24/building-standalone-python-applications-with-pyoxidizer/">executable code&lt;/a>. There is already quite a number of modules to convert code into an executable file. According to Michael Kennedy, the Git repo is so active, that made me to explore what the PyOxidizer is made of. Surprise, Surprise! Its made an amalgamation of Rust and Python, in 80-20 ratio.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>