<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo backend on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/series/hugo-backend/</link><description>Recent content in hugo backend on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:22:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/series/hugo-backend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrated to blogdown</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/10/migrated-to-blogdown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 12:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/10/migrated-to-blogdown/</guid><description>I was using Hugo for static site generation with Beautiful Hugo as a theme. The theme is known for its balancing act between simplicity and proseness for a blog. With Hugo its a fast act to creating and publishing the contents.
It was all good until I wanted to embed a HTML page. iFrame is always there but including the charts, especially interactive ones generated as HTML is tough to embed in the post (at least for me).</description></item><item><title>Hugo Site Deployment Using Github Actions</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/hugo-site-deployment-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 19:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/hugo-site-deployment-using-github-actions/</guid><description>This is a small write up about setting up GitHub Actions to deploy Hugo site.
Table of content How I was deploying it earlier? What was the problem there? How does the GitHub Actions helps us here? How I was deploying it earlier? I used to have 2 commits for any changes.
Changes to the posts HTML documents generated through hugo command What was the problem there?</description></item><item><title>Starting with Jekyll</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/starting-with-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 22:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/05/starting-with-jekyll/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s cool to have a personal website. As a novice, where to start? The cheapest, practical and programmatic option is Github Pages
Cheapest - Free to use GH Pages. You may not get a dedicated domain, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a name.github.io
Practical - You can go for blogger or wordPress for writing a blog post. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get to experience the nitty-gritty involved with running an actual website.
Programmatic - Once you started programming, it will be intriguing to learn something new.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the site!</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/welcome-to-the-site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 19:47:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/04/welcome-to-the-site/</guid><description>This is a new site built on Jekyll, hosted on GitHub.
I came across the GitHub Pages. As the flow looks intriguing, I&amp;rsquo;m trying out this. As a blogger I tried out Wordpress, Blogspot and Medium. The interest to compose a post fizzles out very often. However, I&amp;rsquo;m trying harder to reverse the trend.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes.</description></item></channel></rss>