<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>repost, on Dheepak&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/repost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in repost, on Dheepak&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:10:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/repost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19: Political change on the cards?</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-08-political-changes-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:10:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-08-political-changes-covid/</guid>
      <description>The outbreak is here. Turned into Pandemic, spreading across geographies without much of obstacles. The impact is felt in so many domains, from hospitals to hospitality, from tourism industry to ride-sharing. Governments are scrambling to slow down its spread. The corporates are equipping employees with work-from-home options. Unorganized sector is going for a toss. So, how could the COVID-19 affect the governing bodies?
Late 2010s and the raise of Nationalists The Nationalists or Conservatives or Right wingers are in raise in the 2ndhalf of 2010s, across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Couple of things that went unnoticed</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-08-things-went-unnoticed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:01:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-04-08-things-went-unnoticed/</guid>
      <description>Last July marks the Quadrennial year working in an MNC. These years had taught me several valuable lessons. Learnt either from first-hand experience or learning from others action. What I learnt is that our fundamentals are flawed as several important things are not taught at young age.
There are 2 important things that must be included in curriculum.
Career vs. Job : In earlier generation, its pride to be working with an employer for long duration (say, in terms years or decades).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
