<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experience on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/experience/</link><description>Recent content in Experience on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:48:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/categories/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The birth of my own ADR</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/10/the-birth-of-my-own-adr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/10/the-birth-of-my-own-adr/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday I was talking to my friend about ways to accumulate tuition fees for kids. He suggested going with Chit funds, as they promise 12% returns. I was shocked to hear it from him. We have known each other for over a decade now. Through countless discussions on personal finance, we concluded long back that protecting money is as important as accumulating it. Chit funds are notorious in our society. During my schooldays, chit fund scams were all over the news every other week.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To err is human; to correct is process</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/07/to-err-is-human-to-correct-is-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/07/to-err-is-human-to-correct-is-process/</guid><description>&lt;!-- What is aadhaar; how it is relevant for a 4 year old -->
&lt;p>For those unfamiliar, Aadhaar is a universal identity card (or &lt;a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/government-makes-citizenship-disclaimer-on-new-aadhaar-cards-more-prominent/article67780076.ece">not&lt;/a>). It is a biometric-based 12-digit unique number, more or less covers the entire Indian population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aadhaar translates to &lt;em>foundation&lt;/em> or &lt;em>root&lt;/em>. The Aadhaar number is essential for maintaining access to a bank account or a Demat account, mobile connection, and more. The number follows you like a shadow till death. Heck, the number won&amp;rsquo;t even leave you after death. You would need it at &lt;a href="https://kaashimukthi.com/what-documents-are-required-for-cremation-in-india/">cremation center&lt;/a>, then for the death certificate and for transferring your estate as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Recurring Theme in my life</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/05/a-recurring-theme-in-my-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2025/05/a-recurring-theme-in-my-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>What I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss here is a theme that&amp;rsquo;s recurring all through my life. I ran into some trouble and I lose my sleep for few days, but at an unexpected situation I talk about it to someone and voila there comes a solution. Much worse, the concerned people who I thought I&amp;rsquo;m harming doesn&amp;rsquo;t even take it as a big deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overthinking-leads-to-no-where">Overthinking leads to no where&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When I start simulating the impact of some of my actions, I delve into the extremes, a negative extreme. This at times saves me from potentially embarrassing situations. However, many times I indulge in self harm through overthinking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Investing in real estates</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/05/investing-in-real-estates/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a write up on my thoughts abour real estate as investment. The real estate implies plot as well as the home.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- How it works - big in capital -->
&lt;p>To describe my disinterest towards RE, first we should see how the system works with respect to RE. To make it clear I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about REITs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is entirely unregulated space. Meaning, there is no check and balance to help the consumers. With no regulations, the black money is very very common. As the transaction is under the regulator&amp;rsquo;s radar, there is no place to approach for any type of grievances.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learnings from working with external teams</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/04/learnings-from-working-with-external-teams/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the recent change in the role from data engineer to &lt;a href="https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/03/reflections-on-recent-changes-in-work-place/">lead data engineer&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m regularly interacting with different teams, both upstream and downstream. It had become routine to have meetings with the counterparties to understand their difficulties. After all, we are a tree but a part of a forest.  &lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="diversity-factor">Diversity factor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It might annoy us to hear about diversity from the MNCs again and again. However, for the proper functioning of the organization, it is essential to have associates from various backgrounds. This plurality ensures different ideas and approaches to a problem, which in turn gives the authorities the ability to compare and pick a better, more efficient solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflection on daily journaling</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/02/reflection-on-daily-journaling/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last quarter of 2023 was spent away from family for work related in a nordic country. The country is small. The Population density is much smaller. From the land of crowded spaces, this was taking a toll. Staying away from friends and family adds to this as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just to fight off the boredom and depression, I resumed filling the journal on daily basis. Following are the reflections of the process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How was 2023?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2024/01/how-was-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very common to look back what happened after an event. This post is about looking back at the past year through various criteria,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Personal life&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Career&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hobby&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="personal-life">Personal Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Work-life balance oculd have been better, its not like the employer is squeezing me. But its my ability to give priority to the family. If at all one thing I need to work on this year, that would be more time spent with family and cultivating memories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meetings are bad</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re part of a workforce, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand when I say meetings are bad. How to make it better or avoid it becoming worser? By removing the uncertainity from the equation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="case-1-a-message-from-your-spouse">Case 1: A message from your spouse&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekday. You&amp;rsquo;re in a middle of a task which should be completed in next few hours. Your phone beeps. There is a message from your spouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We need to talk. Come home soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fear + Confusion + Hope = Life?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear--confusion--hope-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear--confusion--hope-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a very, very small post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always wonder if uncertainty is bad, possibly the worst feature of life, or may be a bug in life. But uncertainty is not something new that we tend to experience recently. Since the earliest times, uncertainty has been part of life. Thinking out loud, waking up next morning is as uncertain as the weather.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="fear">Fear&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Earth has gone through several extinctions before taking its current form. According to the experts, it has gone through the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extinction_event">Big Five Mass Extinction&lt;/a>.
Apart from these extinction events, we understand now that many species go kaput every day. We could be the ones on any day, and the day hasn&amp;rsquo;t arrived yet. Recently, a microbe has shown us how brittle we are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Experience with raising PR</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/11/experience-with-raising-pr/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post deals with my experience on contributing to the open source project - Microsoft Documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="my-first-pr">My first PR&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This is not my first PR to an OSS. My very first contribution was to &lt;a href="https://github.com/foambubble/foam/pull/581">foambubble/foam&lt;/a>. The pull request adds licence file to the repo. Yea, I know. This may not qualifies for &lt;em>core&lt;/em> technical task. Nevertheless its my contribution. This lead to my Github badge - &lt;a href="https://github.com/dheepakg?tab=achievements&amp;amp;achievement=pull-shark">Pull Shark&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started interacting with the developers on the fix on April 14&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2021. Foam&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://github.com/riccardoferretti">riccardoferretti&lt;/a> was helpful. After series of conversation and some corrections, my changes were merged on April 19&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> 2021. Just 4 days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fumbling 145 days long kindle reading streak</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/06/fumbling-145-days-long-kindle-reading-streak/</guid><description>&lt;p>If my memory serves right, Snapchat popularised the &lt;em>streak&lt;/em> phenomena. Later on, the amount popularity and stickiness it creates among the user, many companies jumped on the band wagon - fitness trackers, calories trackers and many more. What the streak does is it creates a habit among the users and make them to use the particular service on daily basis. Also, it creates a sense of pride with the longer streak on has.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cross compatibility is key</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2022/05/cross-compatibility-is-key/</guid><description>&lt;p>When my kid was on a mattress, she was hesitant to move around. Later on, with the comfort of the soft surface, she was rolling around without caring about her head getting hurt or gravity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything got changed when we let her crawl on the hard surface in the living room. She was getting hurt quite frequently - sometimes stepping on a toy, or hard landing on her head while rolling on the floor, or simply butting on something at her head level. Slowly, she got learned to avoid those hurting her. These days she evaluates the surfaces before taking another step.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power of Open Data</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/07/power-of-open-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/07/power-of-open-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amidst the pandemic, tracking the daily case numbers from the government bulletin became a habit for us. For a small circle of friends involving 3-4 guys, it&amp;rsquo;s a routine to dissect the numbers and get meaning from the case number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The distance between the decision-makers and us is more than the distance between Moon and Earth. Yet, we discuss as if to guide the entire state. The discussions usually raise some questions on the back story about the rise or fall of numbers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Certified Solution Architect - for whom, why and how</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/04/aws-certified-solution-architect-for-whom-why-and-how/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 09:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2021/04/aws-certified-solution-architect-for-whom-why-and-how/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;em>Certifications are a waste of time&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable as I came across dumps (aka recent questions, question banks). Once you memorize the contents of the question bank, you can score cent percent. &lt;em>Memorise answers and recall them in the exam hall, score a pass mark&lt;/em> - a common theme in schools and colleges. I went through it as there are no alternatives. But in the post-academic stage of life, I was hesitant to follow the same approach in office. My point was simple,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unexpected outcome</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/unexpected-outcome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 19:47:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/09/unexpected-outcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here, I want to discuss about an unexpected outcome from interview. Contrary to the &amp;lsquo;rona times, I felt happy and contented.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The interview is usually a stressful affair. I usually prepare &lt;em>100s&lt;/em> of topics, then the interviewer will bombard me with &lt;em>101&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup>&lt;/em> topic. Well, its just a déjà vu, nothing new with the session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The interviewer was friendly and made me absolutely comfortable, there were no stress-inducing questions, all through the entire discussion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A lost relationship</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/a-lost-relationship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/a-lost-relationship/</guid><description>&lt;p>The relationship lasted for 2 years, 3 months, 11 days. Barring restroom moments, we were together all the time. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about my Pixel 2, which has provided me a wonderful experience on any electronics gadget that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever owned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are few things, worth mentioning here, both positive &amp;amp; negative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Software-hardware, made for each other&lt;/strong> - Even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t used &lt;em>any&lt;/em> flagship mobile till then, I feel P2 showed me how it feels when OS is made for hardware. Literally, there were no lag. The pure android is so much more tasty than any other flavor, particularly better than TouchWiz of Android&lt;sup id="a1">&lt;a href="#f1">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Striving with Contextual speakers</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/striving-with-contextual-speakers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 12:40:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/04/striving-with-contextual-speakers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you connected to WiFi?, isn’t it slow?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First part of above sentence is objectively denotes ‘WiFi’. The second part contextually denotes ‘WiFi’ through the word – ‘it’.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According &lt;a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/context">Merriam-Webster&lt;/a>, Context is defined as,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The parts of a discourse that surround a word or passage and can throw light on its meaning&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Every tech giant is boasting that their digital assistants can understand our contextual conversation. Indeed it is a big step for machines to understand our natural speech.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 2</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is 2&lt;sup>nd&lt;/sup> installment of the story. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to arrange beautiful photos of the last decade. The photos are all captured by me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h5 id="the-foggy-view-of-training-center-on-a-december-morning-the-first-time-i-had-a-taste-of-resort-like-place">The foggy view of training center on a December morning. The first time I had a taste of resort-like place.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://github.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/blob/main/2010s/1-training-days.jpeg?raw=true" alt="The training days">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>2011 - The Training Days&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="the-kevin-mitnick-replied-and-followed-me-after-a-tweet-about-ghost-in-the-wires">The Kevin Mitnick replied and followed me, after a tweet about Ghost in the Wires&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/2-kevin-mitnick-follows.png" alt="Kevin Mitnick">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Kevin Mitnick follows me&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="this-was-one-only-outreach-programme-that-i-took-part-in-the-experience-was-good-eye-opening-it-showed-me-state-of-the-primary-school-education-which-was-frightening">This was one only outreach programme that I took part in. The experience was good eye opening. It showed me state of the primary school education, which was frightening.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/3-sneham-progam.jpg" alt="Outreach Programme">)&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>An Outreach Programme&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="a-bachelor-den-more-or-less-this-was-a-typical-arrangement-of-our-residence-green-thingy-was-the-mosquito-net-without-which-you-cant-protect-your-blood-addition-to-ceiling-fan-we-had-2-table-fans-even-thats-not-enough-for-the-chennai-summer-and-so-we-used-up-the-another-option-check-out-next-photo">A bachelor den. More-or-less this was a typical arrangement of our residence. Green-thingy was the mosquito net, without which you can&amp;rsquo;t protect your blood. Addition to ceiling fan, we had 2 table fans. Even thats not enough for the Chennai summer. And so, we used up the another option. Check out next photo.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/4-bachelor-pad.jpg" alt="Bachelor room">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Bachelor room&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="the-fore-mentioned-green-thingy-enabled-us-to-sleep-on-open-terrace-compared-to-sleeping-on-terrace-the-camp-fire-can-go-aside-dozing-off-while-staring-at-stars--sky-waking-up-to-the-chirping-birds-and-screaming-trains-also-you-should-be-ready-to-run-inside-when-the-rain-drops-in-also-setting-up-of-the-bed-on-terrace-takes-time">The fore mentioned green-thingy enabled us to sleep on open terrace. Compared to sleeping on terrace, the camp-fire can go aside. Dozing off while staring at stars &amp;amp; sky, waking up to the chirping birds and screaming trains. Also, you should be ready to run inside when the rain drops in. Also, setting up of the bed on terrace takes time.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/5-sleeping-terrace.jpg" alt="Sleeping on terrace">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Sleeping on terrace&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="the-chennai-flood-the-natural-calamity-that-i-been-part-of-we-always-change-the-tv-channel-when-the-visuals-of-calamity-is-shown-believe-me-once-you-experienced-it-youll-pray-to-the-lord-even-though-youre-an-atheist">The Chennai Flood. The natural calamity that I been part of. We always change the TV channel when the visuals of calamity is shown; believe me, once you experienced it, you&amp;rsquo;ll pray to the lord, even though you&amp;rsquo;re an atheist.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/6-chennai-flood.jpg" alt="Chennai floods">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Chennai floods&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="my-first-air-travel-i-resented-for-not-getting-the-window-seat-but-after-the-transit-i-got-the-window-seat-to-be-honest-the-aisle-seats-are-much-butter-to-stretch-legs-and-reach-out-to-rest-room">My first air travel. I resented for not getting the window seat. But, after the transit I got the window seat. To be honest the aisle seats are much butter to stretch legs and reach out to rest room.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/7-first-inter-fight.jpg" alt="">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>The first time inside a flight&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="my-favorite-dish-is-dosa-and-im-not-a-fan-of-chocolate-bars-the-first-day-on-the-foreign-land-this-was-the-breakfast-this-acted-as-catalyst-for-me-to-learn-cooking">My favorite dish is dosa. And, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of chocolate bars. The first day on the foreign land, this was the breakfast. This acted as catalyst for me to learn cooking.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/8-first-breakfast-abroad.jpeg" alt="First breakfast">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>First breakfast abroad&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="the-popular-chicago-skyline-i-was-grateful-to-the-weather-god-for-allowing-the-sunshine-on-that-day-water-land-sky-this-photo-reminds-me-of-the-centurions">The popular Chicago Skyline. I was grateful to the weather god for allowing the sunshine on that day. WATER! LAND! SKY! This photo reminds me of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pn49zxXRHhA">Centurions&lt;/a>&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/9-chicago-skyline.jpg" alt="Chicago Skyline">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Chicago Skyline&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="as-a-chennai-resident-i-lived-through-2-seasons---summer--very-hot-summer-but-the-us-of-a-boasted-of-4-seasons---spring-summer-fall--winter-each-season-has-its-own-speciality">As a Chennai resident, I lived through 2 seasons - Summer &amp;amp; very hot summer. But the US of A boasted of 4 seasons - Spring, Summer, Fall &amp;amp; Winter. Each season has its own speciality.&lt;/h5>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spring - life springs back after the brutal winter;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Summer - time when people stay outside of house more than staying in;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fall - the leaves fall down, with colorful display;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Winter - shows that hell needn&amp;rsquo;t be always hot.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/10-fall-colors.jpg" alt="The magical fall colours">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Magical Fall Colours&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="you-remember-prison-break-tv-series-this-is-the-prison-that-keep-appearing-in-the-season-1-its-an-abandoned-prison-in-joliet-il-the-time-we-went-there-some-teenagers-were-tearing-apart-the-fence-and-getting-inside-against-the-_prohibited-_-sign-we-took-handful-of-photos-and-drove-away">You remember Prison Break TV series? This is the prison that keep appearing in the Season 1. It&amp;rsquo;s an abandoned prison in Joliet, Il. The time we went there some teenagers were tearing apart the fence and getting inside against the _prohibited _ sign. We took handful of photos and drove away.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/11-Prison-break.jpg" alt="Prison Break">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Shooting Spot of Prison Break&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h4 id="snow-flakes-this-was-captured-from-my-car-on-a-snowy-day">Snow flakes. This was captured from my car on a snowy day.&lt;/h4>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/12-snow-flake.jpg" alt="Snow time">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>Snow Time&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="this-was-the-view-from-the-backside-of-my-house-when-it-snows-you-can-hardly-see-any-creatures-roaming-around-may-be-in-arctics-or-in-wild-some-animals-could-roam-but-the-social-animal-named-humans-wont-be-seen-when-the-earth-is-black-and-white">This was the view from the backside of my house. When it snows, you can hardly see any creatures roaming around. May be in arctics or in wild some animals could roam. But the social-animal-named-humans won&amp;rsquo;t be seen when the earth is black-and-white.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/13-view-from-home.jpg" alt="View from home">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>View from home&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="my-favoritest-photo-captured-from-my-workplace-its-like-an-entire-ecosystem---lake-stream-road-dead-trees--office-space">My favoritest photo. Captured from my workplace. It&amp;rsquo;s like an entire ecosystem - lake, stream, road, dead trees &amp;amp; office space.&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dheepakg/static-site.images/main/2010s/14-view-from-office.jpg" alt="View from office">&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">&lt;em>View from office&lt;/em>&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>The 2010s - Part 1</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 14:14:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2020/01/the-2010s-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>The 2010&amp;rsquo;s was my 20&amp;rsquo;s. I was in the middle of under graduate course when the decade begun. An average engineering graduate who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what engineering really was or what&amp;rsquo;s the future is offering. The end of year marks the recruitment to my current employer. Yes right, I&amp;rsquo;m with the employer for almost a decade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IIRC 13k was my 1&lt;sup>st&lt;/sup> my first salary. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall how I spent it, guess gave it to my mom. My first smartphone was Galaxy Ace with 142 MB of memory (now there are plenty of apps that comes with larger memory footprint than the phone).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PyConIndia 2019</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 11:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/10/pyconindia-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>My primary source of Python and Python related news was/is &lt;a href="https://talkpython.fm">Python podcast&lt;/a>, since 2016. In 2018, I came to know about Pycon taking place in Cleveland, OH. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zDVlqeOT2XY&amp;amp;list=PLP8GkvaIxJP281FqVlJBgHGyMRvP9NtYN">Dan Bader&amp;rsquo;s vlog on PyCon &amp;lsquo;18&lt;/a> was another pull factor towards the PyCon. Due to the ticket pricing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to it. In H2 of 2018, I returned to India, and was looking forward to attend PyConIndia, which should be affordable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PyConIndia &amp;lsquo;19 is taking place in Chennai, which happened to be my second home. There can&amp;rsquo;t be anymore reason to miss the conference. The ticket booking opened for PyConIndia on one fine day. Then I did booked a ticket, sadly couldn&amp;rsquo;t book the early bird ticket.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yes, humanity exists</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/yes-humanity-exists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/yes-humanity-exists/</guid><description>&lt;p>The social media is made of several bubbles. The bubbles, each of us build around us, with like minded people. With the bubble is well constructed, we live and slowly start believing it is the reflection of the actual world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what happened to me in recent times. There is some negative news keep getting shared to me via whatsapp, twitter or facebook. The negativity comes in the form of political corruption to pedophilia. Slowly and steadily I started believing we are living in place where humanity turned extinct.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Podcast listening 101</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/podcast-listening-101/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 23:17:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/07/podcast-listening-101/</guid><description>&lt;p>Podcast is a audio show, could be anythingranging from interviews to discussions to story telling. The Podcasts became a thing with the iPods. Even the term itself &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p038m811">derived&lt;/a> from the Apple&amp;rsquo;s gadget. Off late, with the arrival of 3&lt;sup>rd&lt;/sup> party apps, more people from Android are attracted, along with the Apple users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Apple, iTunes enables us to listen to Podcast. Google released their own &lt;a href="https://podcasts.google.com/about">app&lt;/a> very recently and the customization is very limited. However, there are tons of apps available through the Podcast producers or third parties.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>