<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COVID-19, on Dheepak's blog</title><link>/tags/covid-19/</link><description>Recent content in COVID-19, on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 19:24:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Essentially, they're non-essentials</title><link>/post/2020-06-14-non-essentials/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 19:24:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-06-14-non-essentials/</guid><description>The future generations must be viewing this as a biggest psychological experiment, worst case scenario and the inhumane practice to save humanity and much more. This is COVID-19 lockdown.
Lockdown was imposed on March 25th2020. Being a social animal, we went through a lot. The ill effects of lockdown ranges from anxiety induced due to potential job loss - historic unemployment rate, potential downturn of investments in coming years, struggling to keep up with daily work-from-home with it&amp;rsquo;s own challenges.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19: Political change on the cards?</title><link>/post/2020-04-08-political-changes-covid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 13:10:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-04-08-political-changes-covid/</guid><description>The outbreak is here. Turned into Pandemic, spreading across geographies without much of obstacles. The impact is felt in so many domains, from hospitals to hospitality, from tourism industry to ride-sharing. Governments are scrambling to slow down its spread. The corporates are equipping employees with work-from-home options. Unorganized sector is going for a toss. So, how could the COVID-19 affect the governing bodies?
Late 2010s and the raise of Nationalists The Nationalists or Conservatives or Right wingers are in raise in the 2ndhalf of 2010s, across the world.</description></item></channel></rss>