<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RaspberryPi on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/raspberrypi/</link><description>Recent content in RaspberryPi on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:35:57 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/raspberrypi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>No more Ad breaks - thanks Pi-hole</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/no-more-ad-breaks-thanks-pi-hole/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 20:12:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2019/06/no-more-ad-breaks-thanks-pi-hole/</guid><description>&lt;p>While browsing through Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s sub in Reddit, I came across &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-hole&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pi-hole is an interesting project, claims to be black hole of Ads. I guess the &lt;em>pi&lt;/em> in the name refers to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi">Raspberry Pi&lt;/a>. As my Pi3 was lying in the corner unused, I went for the Pi-hole installation. Before continuing further on the experience, we need to discuss why the ads are bothering?&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="whats-wrong-with-ads">What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with ads?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>I agree the ads are the revenue source of websites. They are good as long as they don&amp;rsquo;t obstruct the usage, but do they? If not, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have went for browser level Ad blockers in first place. Having an Ad blocker in browser works good. But, this may impact performance of the browser. There are &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-chrome-ad-blockers-extensions-api/">news that claims&lt;/a> Google may break the working of Ad blockers in Chrome. The situation of smartphones are mush worse. Especially, in Android. There are no regulation, even in the popular apps, the Ads are placed in every available real estate. The expectation is to hijack your attention when you accidentally touch these spaces. There are apps which can protect you from ads, you&amp;rsquo;ve to sideload them, but sideloading an app is not a safe option.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>