<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncertainity on Dheepak's blog</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/uncertainity/</link><description>Recent content in Uncertainity on Dheepak's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:29:33 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dheepakg.github.io/tags/uncertainity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meetings are bad</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/meetings-are-bad/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re part of a workforce, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand when I say meetings are bad. How to make it better or avoid it becoming worser? By removing the uncertainity from the equation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="case-1-a-message-from-your-spouse">Case 1: A message from your spouse&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a busy weekday. You&amp;rsquo;re in a middle of a task which should be completed in next few hours. Your phone beeps. There is a message from your spouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We need to talk. Come home soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fear + Confusion + Hope = Life?</title><link>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear--confusion--hope-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dheepakg.github.io/post/2023/12/fear--confusion--hope-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a very, very small post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always wonder if uncertainty is bad, possibly the worst feature of life, or may be a bug in life. But uncertainty is not something new that we tend to experience recently. Since the earliest times, uncertainty has been part of life. Thinking out loud, waking up next morning is as uncertain as the weather.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="fear">Fear&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Earth has gone through several extinctions before taking its current form. According to the experts, it has gone through the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extinction_event">Big Five Mass Extinction&lt;/a>.
Apart from these extinction events, we understand now that many species go kaput every day. We could be the ones on any day, and the day hasn&amp;rsquo;t arrived yet. Recently, a microbe has shown us how brittle we are.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>